<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="inherownwrite.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="inherownwrite.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-15T00:45:58-07:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">In Her Own Write</title><subtitle>Eternal malaise of the soul.</subtitle><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><entry><title type="html">Dissecting male attention in business terms</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/03/14/microdosing-male-attn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dissecting male attention in business terms" /><published>2025-03-14T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-14T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/03/14/microdosing-male-attn</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/03/14/microdosing-male-attn.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/b&gt; The truth of the matter is, I didn’t want to be this cynical and Machiavellian about love. Relationships are not supposed to be zero-sum games. But when the game is rigged against people like us, and when men take advantage of the trust and care we give them, this approach allows you to enjoy male attention while keeping yourself safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disclaimer No. 2:&lt;/b&gt; The second truth is, as my friend Angie says, I hate men who are mfs. And most men are mfs. None of us need male attention to survive... but, boy, is it fun. It’s like weed. You use it to feel alive, to get that high, but don’t become so addicted that you start thinking, &quot;I need him.&quot; Use it sparingly; don’t let the drug use you. You control it—always remember that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered the disclaimers, here’s how to safely microdose male attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;1. Don’t Love the Players, Love the Game&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on your strategy and personal goals, not on any one person. Ask yourself: What do I want from this? A relationship? Instant gratification? Or just attention I didn&apos;t get as a kid? In business, the goal is to stay objective and focus on the long-term strategy—not getting emotionally entangled in the success or failure of any one deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing that can happen is losing yourself in someone. When you love the player (not the game), the ship starts sinking, and you lose yourself. But when you focus on the game, you know when to leave, when to “jump ship”—and that gives you clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loving the game means each player serves a purpose, and you can walk away when they no longer serve you. It’s about maintaining control and realizing that control doesn’t mean manipulation—it means having the option to walk away whenever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if a deal goes sour, reflect on what you could have done differently. That makes the experience about learning, not about loss. Like I said, love should never be a zero-sum game—attachment makes it one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;2. Diversification in Investments: Always Have a Roster&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a roster is the best way to prevent attachment. I made the mistake of letting my roster go once I found someone I thought was worth investing in—but I was wrong. It’s like sales: nothing is finalized until the deal is closed. Until you cuff or get cuffed, you have the right to have a roster. Having multiple options prevents you from pouring all your emotional energy into one person (your &quot;stock&quot;) and getting too attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re focused on just one player, all your emotional eggs are in that basket. Sometimes, you’re reluctant to cut your losses because you feel like walking away will cost you everything. This makes relationships a zero-sum game because you’ve invested more than you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of having a roster is not to manipulate your players or toy with their feelings. It is simply to retain sobriety and remind yourself that you are in control. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;3. Microdose Your Attention&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the sales strategy comes in: drip-feeding value to keep the other party interested, without giving everything upfront. Think of it as supply and demand. When you offer something valuable but in small doses, it creates a sense of demand—keeping them coming back for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you over-deliver too soon, they take you for granted. But when you limit access, they begin to see you as high-value and realize you won’t tolerate disrespect or stick around for scraps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to the roster—since you aren’t giving anyone everything at once, they won’t get tired of you. They won’t have the opportunity to take you for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t put all your eggs in one basket. It&apos;s a simple investment strategy: diversify your “portfolio.” When one stock disappoints, you move on without losing everything. Unless you’re 120% sure about a particular stock’s value or loyalty, never go all in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Will This Fulfill You?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it depends. If you’re looking for high returns, maybe not. But if you want low risks, this approach should work well. It leaves room for the possibility of reward—romantic or otherwise. It&apos;s basic investment economics: high-risk, high-return; low-risk, low-return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re seeking deep emotional connections and long-term investing, this “microdosing” approach may feel unsatisfying or superficial. But here’s my take: After experiencing deep emotional connections and still being severely let down, I don’t think it’s worth it. Men (mfs) have mastered enjoying attention without expecting commitment. We should do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shouldn’t seek star-crossed love from men with the emotional depth of a kiddie pool. Instead, seek multitudes within yourself. This strategy helps maintain balance and manage the expectation that not every connection needs to be deep and life-changing. I don’t need another man roaming this Earth with the knowledge of my deepest, darkest secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of whether this microdosing strategy will fulfill you ultimately comes down to personal preference. Understanding this business-savvy approach to male attention reflects boundaries, emotional self-preservation, and risk management. After all, men are not FDIC insured.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="Opinion" /><summary type="html">Disclaimer: The truth of the matter is, I didn’t want to be this cynical and Machiavellian about love. Relationships are not supposed to be zero-sum games. But when the game is rigged against people like us, and when men take advantage of the trust and care we give them, this approach allows you to enjoy male attention while keeping yourself safe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">涅瓦河的隱秘</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/chinese/creative/2025/02/16/neva.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="涅瓦河的隱秘" /><published>2025-02-16T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/chinese/creative/2025/02/16/neva</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/chinese/creative/2025/02/16/neva.html">&lt;p&gt;「那裡，在寥廓的海波之旁 &lt;br&gt;
他站著，充滿了偉大的思想，&lt;br&gt;
向遠方凝視。在他前面&lt;br&gt;
河水廣闊地奔流……」&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;這是雅立在涅瓦河邊，彼得大帝青銅像的描述。涅瓦河，見證了聖彼特堡的榮辱與興衰。那河畔的建築經歷了革命的風雨，目睹了一個國家的成長。在雄偉的涅瓦河邊, 在濔漫著寒冷乾燥的氣味的冬天，看著大江東去，沙皇的風光一時，令人不禁嘆息。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;涅瓦河位於聖彼特堡的中心，站在岸邊，可以重現逝去的沙俄大帝國王朝的輝煌：兩旁的教堂，是王朝為下的歷史古蹟。其中的濺血教堂，擁有東正教堂的穹頂，雖說別具色彩，但色澤冷黯無神，暗帶悲傷。俄羅斯中世紀的建築風格，日漸失修的朱紅血色外牆，彷彿經歷了無盡委屈。所謂的「濺血」，是早在革命之前，19世紀沙皇亞歷山大二世在教堂旁被刺殺，而命名為血濺教堂的哀悼。如今，宗教在人民的生活當中不再重要，聖彼特堡的教堂原有的威嚴已經早在俄國革命中被洗劫一空。這是俄國歷史上第一場的罪與罰，是往後俄國革命的預兆，就發生在涅瓦河的岸邊。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;涅瓦河的另一邊，彼得保羅教堂的對面，還有一個雄踞在旁的歷史古蹟—冬宮。金碧輝煌的裝飾配上高貴淡綠的外牆，從涅瓦河邊望過去，已經感受到沙俄皇朝的威嚴，令人肅然起敬。這是歷代沙皇自18世紀以來定居的皇宮，奢華設計目不暇給。現在變成了博物館的冬宮，任人進入參觀：幻想童話般的皇家在此宮殿裡生活，兩個世紀前多麼的富麗堂皇！然而，這個雕欄玉砌的建築背後，蘊藏著俄國有血有淚的辛酸史—十月革命的洗禮。血腥星期日於冬宮廣場發生，在民眾與軍隊的衝突之中，一千多人在此喪生。1917年，工人軍人為推翻臨時政府，突襲冬宮，把一個沉睡中的民族喚醒，冬宮不復從前的純真，變成了人們對貴族皇朝所仇恨的象徵。正當國家動盪，民憤四處的同時，涅瓦河面結成冰，殘冬只遺下了一份血腥腥的滄桑。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;冬天過後，涅瓦河帶著逐漸融去的冰塊流淌。新的春風景氣吹遍聖彼特堡。在這個經歷了三次革命的城市，大地萬象更新，新的政府為人民帶來新的希望，忘卻舊代王朝的腐敗衰落。革命就是如此簡單嗎？把舊社會打個流花落水，換來的只剩頹垣敗；推翻一個王朝容易，但建立一個政府困難。歷史重是驚人的相似，涅瓦河照舊奔流，警告俄羅斯不要重蹈覆轍。這段令人唏噓的歷史，恐怕只剩下涅瓦河得以保存三百年前的樣貌了。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="Chinese" /><category term="Creative" /><summary type="html">「那裡，在寥廓的海波之旁 他站著，充滿了偉大的思想， 向遠方凝視。在他前面 河水廣闊地奔流……」</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Thrilling, Confusing, Short-Lived, Torrid Love Affair</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/anecdote/2025/02/14/My-Thrilling-Confusing-Short-Lived-Torrid-Love-Affair.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Thrilling, Confusing, Short-Lived, Torrid Love Affair" /><published>2025-02-14T23:15:35-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T23:15:35-08:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/anecdote/2025/02/14/My-Thrilling-Confusing-Short-Lived-Torrid-Love-Affair</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/anecdote/2025/02/14/My-Thrilling-Confusing-Short-Lived-Torrid-Love-Affair.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Valentine’s Day. In the past 96 hours, I have experienced one of the most thrilling, insane, upsetting yet rewarding week I have ever had. I had quite a love affair with venture capitalism. Or perhaps “a brief flirtation” would describe what happened more accurately, but it is my crashout so I get to call it whatever I want. I also feel like writing a four-thousand-word blogpost for “a brief flirtation” would make me sound insane. And for those that are updated with the recent ronilore and very disappointed, yes, it was clickbait; but please hear me out, as the lore does go hard on this one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not know, I am quite the CS major. I am a very engineering-minded, problem-solving-oriented person, but I am also a yapper. Sometimes I find myself pondering if this is the right career path for me, as the stereotypical engineer are usually socially inept losers that only communicates through discord. But that does not apply to me, and I don’t know if that is truly “my calling”. I enjoy what I do, and over the years I have adapted into the space a little more than what I’d like to believe, but I am still not fully convinced that I should be doing SWE my entire life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, naturally, I decided to try out some of the entrepreneurship classes offered at Berkeley. To be honest, I am initially not even that interested in founding startups and stuff. I am not a risk taker. I believed that it is hard for rookies like me to break into investing/ entrepreneurship because a) I don’t have the financial literacy to do it, b) I don’t believe in investing as my main source of income, and c) I have seen too many cases where investments (stocks, real estate, just anything tbh) turn south, and I don’t think I want to gamble with my hard-earned money like that. But, since I am at Silicon Valley, where technology entrepreneurship is actually THE way to make an impact and make a name of yourself (a bit of an American Dream there eh), I decided to dip my toes in and try it out a little. Berkeley’s entrepreneurship program is like, their flagship stuff. Not every school has the resources for these classes. I personally cannot conceive that many unique ideas, but if somebody else comes up with something cool, I don’t mind joining a team and help out with my skills as an engineer. So that is my mindset coming into the whole entrepreneurial thing. You can say my reason is somewhat superficial: I am not here just to make money, I am here to make a lasting impact that can make people’s lives easier, even if at a miniscule level. It was quite innocent of a mindset to get into the whole entrepreneurship thingy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And boy, did I try my best. I got into the SCET program at Berkeley, where they basically incubate undergrads to come up with their own startups, and potentially receive funding to turn their ideas into venture-backed companies. I really wanted the SCET certificate because I thought it would help me with applying to grad school some day, if I ever decide to go. And so, for my last semester as an undergrad, I am taking 3 entrepreneur classes: a class about how to start a startup with sustainability and ethics in mind, a class all about the business and steps in creating a tech startup, and a class about leveraging data as a way to stand out from the crowd and have a good business model. And I was going to only take 2 out of the 3 classes (for the certificate), but I loved all three classes so much that I decided to keep all 3. Was it an overkill? Most definitely. But this is lowkey the first time during my 2 years at Berkeley where I feel like I am truly taking classes for the sake of learning, not to fulfill the graduation requirement or fill up my units. Like, oh my god. I am actually interested in learning all of this. I don’t get to learn this from anywhere else, but the #1 school with undergrad founders. So yes, it was wonderful, and I was so ready to commit to this program, even if I am not going to be an actual entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that was my plan up till last week. I have been consistently participating in classes, I crack a couple of jokes during class here and there, I get called out by my professors for being on the laptop or whatever, but it’s been going alright. Then, last week, as I was lining up to kiss the professor’s ass after lecture, one of the TAs called me over and said she has something to discuss with me. She is the TA for two out of the three classes I am in, so I suppose that I have made an impression. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, Veronica, right?” &lt;br&gt;

“Yes, am I in trouble or something?” I try to recall if I used AI for the last assignment.&lt;br&gt;

“Do you have any experience with venture capitalism?”&lt;br&gt;

“Um, I have worked at a startup before, so I guess?”&lt;br&gt;

“Well… okay it doesn’t matter. There is this venture capitalism competition that is happening next Saturday, and a team still needs two people. So, I want to see if you are interested in joining the team.”&lt;br&gt;

“Um… sure.”&lt;br&gt;

“There is a workshop happening right now, so we will need to go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she was packing, I texted my friends that I had dinner/ alcohol plans with. I told them some crazy opportunity just came up so I couldn’t make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rushed to the workshop, and by the time I got there, it was time for the mock presentation for the teams to present to the (actual) venture capitalists to show them what they’ve learn in the past three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you, I just got there, and I lowkey don’t know a single VC term. I didn’t know TAM, SAM, SOM, or LTV:CAC ratio, just any of the crazy terms. I was an eager noob. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met the two guys that are left in the team. There were 5 people originally, 3 dropped out due to various unreasonable reasons, a girl from a different team joined, and now they need two more people. Let’s just call those two, Andy and Caleb. They were super nice, super accommodating, and reassured me that they won’t be mad even if I don’t know what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it in very vulgar terms, I rawdogged the mock presentation. I went in there with my super cute outfit and boot heels, I told the venture capitalists that I have an engineering background, and I brought in all the excitement that I had with this crazy fun opportunity, and I acted as professional and business-y as I could. I used some technical engineering terms, I questioned the founder’s idea behind the AI use, and I raised questions about their business model. The VCs did not grill me too hard, although the guy said I had “too much energy”. But the VC lady loved it, and I think I did well. It was such an incredible experience, and I was almost starstrucked with talking to actual, professional VCs working in Silicon Valley. I mean, these are the actual sharks of shark tank. They were a little mean sometimes, but, they earned the right to be mean. And they are business people that sign million-dollar deals, making million dollar decisions. Of course they are a little mean, why wouldn’t they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a bit of a Cinderella moment for me. Before this opportunity, I accepted my fate as a CS major that is destined to be the builder/ engineer, but never the presenter. I have always knew that my strongest skillset lies in the way I make connections and network with people, as well as improvisational comedy and just being a crazy public speaker (due to the lack of social cues). I am aware of my talents/ skillsets, but I also wanted the safest way to make money/ an impact, plus I am pretty good at math. So I thought I could just put my dreams of being a professional social person on the backlog for now. But with this world of venture capitalism, it combines my greatest two interests in life: the theatrics of persuasion and public speaking, and also the technicality in engineering and innovation. Venture capitalism is truly the best of two worlds. I use my engineering domain knowledge to make business decisions. Plus, it’s technically not my money. It’s the LPs. So, I thought this might be my true, true calling. And it is not too late discovering your true, true calling three weeks into the last semester of your undergrad, right? I still have the rest of my life to figure it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing. I enjoyed chilling with the two teammates, and I had a nice time briefing texting the other girl. Let’s call her Blaire. Andy offered to teach me a little more of the VC jargon/ terms that’s foreign to me, an offer which I gladly accepted. Caleb is a sophomore that is super sweet and has this almost childlike charm that reminded me of a younger version of myself, before I got jaded and disillusioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some personal stuff happened over the weekend, but I was still so excited for the competition. I even had Valentine’s Day blocked out for this competition, so I know I won’t be alone. Fast forward to Tuesday, I texted the groupchat if anyone wants to hang out and teach me a little bit more for the competition. Andy DMed me, and said he is down to come over and help me. We live in the same building, so it is not that hard to hang out. I thought we were going to the study lounge, but he straight asked me my room number. Naturally, I gave him my room number. He’s like “I’ll hurry over” and came at around 10pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was quite adamant about taking his shoes off, I am not sure why. I gave him some spare slippers, he tried and told me they were too small for him. We both laughed. He threw his dirty ass backpack onto my bed, and sat on it when his street clothes. I was pretty startled, as my bedsheets were very clean and shouldn’t be touched with outside stuff. You know what I mean. But he just treated the place like it’s his. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down and went over the VC razor checklist. He went over the details, and I asked questions. He is an econ major, and when we talked about the market and stuff, I gave him the chance to mansplain macroeconomics to me. He gladly took the offer and started yapping about government bonds and stuff. Despite the fact that it is all basic information any econ major would know, I was quite impressed. I was also impressed by the fact that he is willing to sit down and explain all that to me. But after around 45 minutes of serious learning, I had the overwhelming urge to overshare. And I asked for his consent to overshare, he said yes. I went on a two hour rant on things that had happened in the past couple of days, and he was deeply interested in listening. And afterwards, he went on a rant about his roommate. It was really fun as I had a lot of pent-up anger and needed that to be released. We yapped until midnight, which was when we got a noise complaint. But that did not stop us, we just went to a study room to continue talking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He briefly explained some cool VC terms after switching rooms. I learned about the “pro-rata right”, which was a VC jargon that guarantees the same amount of shares the VC would have when more investors come in. It is for anti-dilution prevention, and it prevents the scene in the social network where Eduardo Saverin’s shares in Facebook was diluted after millions of new shares were distributed. It was really cool. It was interesting though, he said “pro-rata” like “pro-ray-da”, so I assumed it’s spelled as “pro-vader” or “pro-razor”. But when I googled it, it’s pronounced as “pro-rah-tah”, so I got confused. Either way, I’m glad I learned all that from him, I probably wouldn’t have the opportunity to learn any of this anyways. And side note, while I was doing my research writing this, and I discovered that Eduardo Saverin is now a venture capitalist and is the richest man in Singapore with his 2% share of Facebook. He started out as the co-founder of Facebook and is now helping out other startups. It’s all quite poetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the serious parts of our conversations, I talked about my fear for investing and how I prefer “working earnestly” as my means of production. I was obviously implying that investing is not a way to make money “earnestly”, because it is like gambling and I don’t think I am capable of making good decisions with my limited knowledge. But he raised a really good point that stayed in my mind ever since: “you cannot create generational wealth just by working hard for someone else.” And that makes a lot of sense to me all of a sudden. Generational wealth, or generational impact just by following the lead of somebody. This is why Berkeley is so keen on undergrads doing startups anyways. They want organic, home-grown innovation. And that’s so cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I do want to defend venture capitalism as like, quite an interesting and niche sector within investment and finance. It is high-risk, high-return, and they are investing in companies and make people’s dreams come true. With the stock markets and typical investing, you are not contributing to make a lasting impact on somebody/ something. But with VC, you are here to disrupt and make an impact. You get to make million-dollar decisions and take chances with helping somebody out. Obviously, VCs want high yield returns, but that comes with any business deals. I am a little swept off my feet with all these new and exciting concepts, only at places like Silicon Valley, y’know? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond venture capitalism, we talked so much about the dating scene and hookup culture. I really enjoyed the conversation as I don’t really get a candid, platonic male perspective, and he doesn’t get that with women either. It was such a 2-3AM conversation. Oh and, we also talked about classical music. I forgot how the conversation started, but we were just saying how we don’t have friends to go to recitals with, and we made the crazy decision to buy tickets to this concert the next week together. It was nice, I was genuinely making a friend. We ended up talking till 4AM. We yapped till our eyes cannot open, it was crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days leading up to the competition, I was actively recruiting for members. I invited a guy that was great at public speaking at one of the the SCET classes, who accepted them later left the team due to a scheduling conflict. I also told my professor, who is a full-time venture capitalist, about the opportunities. He was super supportive about it and gave me some tips with how it went. I also bought a suit off Amazon. I am an ENGINEER, there is like zero occasions where I need to wear a suit. Even at networking events, dressing in business casual would be deemed as overdressing. Techbros just show up in hackathon hoodies and call it a day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days before the competition, the TA found a new member. Let’s call him Dhinesh. We were running out of time, so Dhinesh was our last bet. Dhinesh and Blaire had beef and she didn’t get fully into it. And when I dmed Andy and asked why, he said Dhinesh is “fruity and weird”. I want to take his word for the weird part, but I can’t help but feel like it is very mean of me to judge somebody’s character based on whether they are fruity or not. That’s just thinly veiled homophobia, and that does not fly with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caleb and I were the only ones texting in the groupchat. Mind you, Andy and Blaire are the two more capable, and more well-versed in the VC jargon, but they were virtually silent days leading up to the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all just so sketchy. Andy, Blaire, Dhinesh and I are all seniors, while Caleb is a sophomore. I can imagine Caleb being confused with why these senior citizens are fighting like highschoolers. It was such a messy mess and I feel bad for Caleb the most. He just a baby. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there is no other way, I added Dhinesh to the groupchat. He is quite capable and enthusiastic about it. Andy and Blaire are still mute, and the three of us plan to meet the day before the competition. But 5 people were the minimum requirement, so we could just wing it. I was there to participate, to meet the VC judges and to learn more about this exciting, niche industry. What’s the worse that could happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dhinesh and I met on Google meet, the night before the competition. Caleb added everybody on a google meet link, but only the two of us showed up. We had a good time introducing ourselves, while I sorta understand what they meant by “weird”, but I still have an open heart and mind to collaborating with him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 30 minutes into the meeting, Andy hopped in out of nowhere. He told us that he and Blaire decided to withdraw, so we will not be participating. I was shocked, but I tried to keep my cool. I tend to process my feelings a lot later after my fight/ flight mode gets triggered. But Dhinesh was visibly shocked and confused. He cleared his schedule to dive into this competition head first, and I did too. 24 hours before it starts, someone decides to withdraw: the people that got screwed over decides to screw somebody else over the same way they got screwed over. He stayed to banter a little though, and we kept it very civil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours after that weird call, Dhinesh calls me to discuss what happens next. The both of us are confused. I sort of defended Andy and Blaire’s decision, as I am still trying to see the good in people and always give others the benefit of the doubt (until they cross the line). But Dhinesh and Blaire had beef tracing all the way back to freshman year, so he was not having it. And hearing how Dhinesh is not having it makes me realize that maybe I should not just sit here and agree with what others want, disregarding what I want in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, Dhinesh and I decided to hit Caleb up and ask him how he feels. Caleb wanted to do the competition so bad, and technically it is three against two, so we want to move forward with it. I also called Blaire on the phone, but she didn’t pick up. Mind you, I haven’t met her a single time up to this point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the emergency meeting, each of us explained our thoughts on how to move forward. Andy said this is not what he signed up for with the competition, he doesn’t want to be the teacher for this last-minute team. Blaire said we don’t know the terms enough and we don’t know each other well enough to be in a team together. Caleb wants to take a stab at it and he doesn’t mind the outcome regardless. Dhinesh wants to do it and expressed his frustration with just joining and team and also getting told to withdraw last minute. Last but not least, if I were a character I would probably call myself Eliza or something, but I said I just want to learn and this seemed so fun. So we voted, and 3 out of 5 people want to continue. So we worked on preparing for the competition a little, only for 30 minutes. But you can tell that Andy and Blaire were not having it. I try not to think too hard during the meeting, because I really try to see the best in people and I don’t think Andy and Blaire thinks we are beneath them necessarily. But the truth is, other teams had 3 weeks to prepare and we didn’t. And that is not anybody’s fault except for the ones that left the two guys. And Andy was the one that wrote the email saying we are withdrawing, but he didn’t want to look bad with the un-withdrawal. I could somewhat empathize but disagree with their mindsets, but it is just not fair for them to take away our chances of doing the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Caleb, Dhinesh and I talk in the groupchat about the preparation meeting. I was pulling all the strings together and messaging everybody with our plans. At around 4pm, Andy and Blaire texts the groupchat saying they have, once again, decide to withdraw. They dropped two random people in the groupchat and said, “here are two people that we found that could do the competition with y’all. Good luck.” Dhinesh and I were stressed out of our minds. Let’s call these two people, Fredrik and Gauri. I dmed the two of them, greeting them and asking them if they can meet at the library at 5pm. Fredrik responded enthusiastically. Gauri was very confused with what was happening, and asked me to explain everything. I did, and she told me that she doesn’t want to join a competition 12 hours before it begins hastily. She said she would’ve loved to join from the beginning, but given how messy it is, she doesn’t think it would be a good idea. I completely understand and small talked a little, she seems like an amazing person. Fredrik said he is available to meet with Dhinesh and I on campus at 5pm. We are still one person short, but I suppose that I could still do it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to my TA about the entire situation. She informed me that our team could NOT move forward with Fredrik in the team. He competed in the competition last year and caused a lot of drama. So, in the end, the two members that “joined the groupchat” could not actually join the group, and we could not move forward with the competition. The organizers (TA included) emailed Andy and Blaire, and they were also informed that they are unable to move the team forward without the two of them in the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met up with Dhinesh after class and called Caleb. We were actively traumabonding. We drafted up a sincerely apology of all the inconvenience caused (despite the drama not caused by us), and we wished them a nice, smooth competition the next day. All of that was sincere and true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Dhinesh and I were not satisfied with the outcome. We cleared our schedules, stayed up till 2am to study for the competition, and we don’t want other people to sabotage our learning opportunity. So we decided to finish up our VC learnings and draft up a term sheet for the competition, even if we are not competing anymore. We went to get frozen yogurt after deciding all that, and we sat in a student lounge completing all our due diligence with the competition materials. We learned all the business terms together and drafted up a pretty solid term sheet, if I do say so myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rarely do things just for the sake of learning, it is always for a grade, a certificate, or to look good. But this is the one instance where I am genuinely learning for the sake of learning. Perhaps it is to feel better about dropping out of the competition, or to learn everything “out-of-spite” so I don’t feel like I am beneath Andy and Blaire. But it didn’t matter, I had so much fun and I learned so much about the business terms with startups and investments. Now I can tell people I have drafted up term sheets before, and I won’t be ripped off at car dealerships anymore. Dhinesh was also incredibly motivated to learn, so, I am glad I had him to learn with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also talked a lot of shit about Blaire. Dhinesh told me that Blaire acted cold and stand-offish towards him since the beginning. And to be real with you, I think I understand what Andy meant we they said Dhinesh is “kinda off”; he goes on his phone when I’m talking to him and farted multiple times. The amount of dirt he said about Blaire was also just, a little much. I was matching his energy, but I do feel a bit bad talking shit about a girl that I haven’t even met. But this isn’t high school. This isn’t “popular kids don’t play with weird losers”. It is rather juvenile to refuse to collaborate with someone smart simply because you find their vibe to be “kinda off”, or had drama with almost three years ago. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so tired by the end of the night, my accent was slipping. I was on power-saving mode. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I texted Andy the next day (which is today), telling him not to feel too bad about it. He is still a super knowledgeable finance bro/ budding venture capitalist, so I want to introduce my CEO on a separate startup project (for the entrepreneurship classes) to him and ask for some advice. He thanked me and we are still cool; we are still going to the recital next Friday together after all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I walked away without burning a single bridge, something I try my best to do in every situation. But I probably won’t be close friends with any of these people anyway. This is probably not my crowd. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave this crazy, thrilling world of venture capitalism and business like Nick Carraway leaving New York. My mind was absolutely blown, but my heart was incredibly let down. It debunked some of my assumptions— that business/ finance is not just about being ruthless and insane, it could also be a platform that leverages money to make people’s dreams come true; but it has also confirmed my hypothesis— that the business world is, at its core, dark, cutthroat, and evil. It’s full of fake people backstabbing each other. And at the end of the day, it’s every man for himself. I get it, but I also cannot believe how it played out. But if I can’t make a LinkedIn post out of this experience, the least I can do is write a blogpost about it. And that is exactly what I am doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, software engineering is most definitely still my calling, for now. But I am open to new opportunities and would love to rekindle this affair with venture capitalism some time. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="Anecdote" /><summary type="html">Happy Valentine’s Day. In the past 96 hours, I have experienced one of the most thrilling, insane, upsetting yet rewarding week I have ever had. I had quite a love affair with venture capitalism. Or perhaps “a brief flirtation” would describe what happened more accurately, but it is my crashout so I get to call it whatever I want. I also feel like writing a four-thousand-word blogpost for “a brief flirtation” would make me sound insane. And for those that are updated with the recent ronilore and very disappointed, yes, it was clickbait; but please hear me out, as the lore does go hard on this one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rossmoor Speech</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/06/02/rossmoor-speech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rossmoor Speech" /><published>2024-06-02T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2024-06-02T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/06/02/rossmoor-speech</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/06/02/rossmoor-speech.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear esteemed guests, members of the Rossmoor Scholarship Foundation, donors, and scholars,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with great honor and gratitude that I stand before you as a former recipient of the Rossmoor Scholarships. My name is Veronica, and I cannot believe that it has already been a year since I have received the awards in this very room.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I would like to congratulate all the Rossmoor Scholars. If you are a recipient, please take a moment to pat yourself on the back for all the hard work that has brought you to this point. The donors and members of Rossmoor took the time to get to know you as an individual, and they care enough to offer financial assistance to invest in you and your future. Receiving this award meant so much to me, especially as a community college graduate, as it was one of the first few moments where I don’t feel subpar to a 4-year college student. Standing here today, I felt seen not just as a student, but as a person who has proven their ability to succeed. I want you to feel the same way; you were hand-picked by someone who believes in you. Congrats. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here is a little bit more about me. I wasn’t the quote-unquote nerd or teacher’s pet back in high school. I even looked down on those people, calling them try-hards. Instead, I was the class clown. Just to give you an idea, I printed out Facebook pictures of my English teacher with his ex-girlfriend back in 8th grade because he gave me a talking-to. I loved making people laugh, and I thought I was being edgy and cool. Looking back, it was immature of me to judge others, as I, myself, had become a try-hard and a teacher’s pet at DVC. I decided that I wanted more than chuckles and giggles from my classmates. I reflected on my priorities in life and changed my approach to school. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flash-forward to the summer of last year. I worked super hard and finished with a 4.0 at DVC. I even secured a job before I started at Berkeley, as an iOS engineer at Quizlet. You guys know the app, right? I assume that most of you are either rising freshmen or juniors in college, and let me tell you, those were two of the best summers I have ever had. Free from the shackles of studying and college applications, I could finally breathe.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But little did I know, the real challenge was waiting for me at Berkeley. Here is a five-word horror story for you: I almost got a C. *gasps* Hey, don’t judge me; I was working part-time and busy being an officer for a club. So cut me some slack here, okay? And no, I wasn’t partying; electrical engineering majors don’t get to do that. Not only were the classes fifty times harder, it was also recruitment season. It’s like applying to colleges, but worse. This time around, companies get to test you on the things school never taught you, they inspect you under a microscope during the interviews, and if they don’t like you, they can just ghost you without explanation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that my first semester of college is behind me, I can confidently tell you what I did wrong: I overcommitted myself to things. I was working so hard to build the perfect resume that I ended up burning myself out. Here’s the main piece of bad news I want to share today: the grind never ends. Just when you think your work is done, another challenge presents itself. The “I’ve made it!” feeling typically lasts for a few weeks tops, then life hits you with another tough midterm or job application rejection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here’s the good news: the grind never ends. And by “the grind,” I am referring to the pursuit of passions and goals. When I was working with a Stanford-educated engineering manager, I told her that I hoped to reach that point in life where I could just stop striving and be satisfied. She replied that what I was describing sounded like retirement. Yet, when I look at someone like her, I think, “Wow, that’s who I want to become.” She candidly shared that she also admires her mentors and aspires to be like them. As long as there’s something within you to improve, you must keep aiming higher. It’s not a competition, but a hunger for growth. And that is the essence of ambition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, all of this may sound extremely tiring. I’m not suggesting you wake up at 5 AM and start brainstorming your next Silicon Valley startup; think of it this way: your career isn’t a sprint, it’s a marathon. This upcoming summer is a perfect time to relax and reflect on your future. But after that, brace yourself for the big decisions and obstacles ahead. Life is tough, but so are you. And in case you are wondering, I am doing a lot better now. I stepped down from the officer position to fully invest in my classes and my work at Quizlet, which I both find to be equally fulfilling. I went from a jokester who didn’t take school seriously, to a try-hard who took everything a little too serious to the point of burned out, and finally, to somebody who is steadily building her blossoming career. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might look at me, and think, “Wow, Veronica has it all figured out!” Or, “Hm, Veronica seems really insecure about her accomplishments.” Both perspectives are somewhat true. I’m proud of how far I’ve come and could talk about my experiences at Berkeley and Quizlet for hours, yet I remain constantly ambitious and hungry for more.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the last call to action I have for you. Number one, I strongly recommend keeping in touch with the Rossmoor community after today, with a biyearly email or something, so they know you appreciate them as much as they appreciate you. Not to be cheesy, but, a heart full of gratitude is a heart full of joy. Number two, promise yourself to remember the emotions you feel today, all the pride and joy.  Remember how nice it felt when you picked out the outfit you’re wearing, and when you come up to take pictures on this stage with the guests. When times are rough, remind yourself of today, how wondrous it is to be recognized and awarded by the lovely folks of Rossmoor. Let that fuel your mind, body, and soul. When the road gets tough, remind yourself how much you deserve this, how hard you’ve worked to get here. And as Shakespeare said it, the world is your oyster. Work hard, and the pearl is yours. Thank you. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Dear esteemed guests, members of the Rossmoor Scholarship Foundation, donors, and scholars,   It is with great honor and gratitude that I stand before you as a former recipient of the Rossmoor Scholarships. My name is Veronica, and I cannot believe that it has already been a year since I have received the awards in this very room.    Before I begin, I would like to congratulate all the Rossmoor Scholars. If you are a recipient, please take a moment to pat yourself on the back for all the hard work that has brought you to this point. The donors and members of Rossmoor took the time to get to know you as an individual, and they care enough to offer financial assistance to invest in you and your future. Receiving this award meant so much to me, especially as a community college graduate, as it was one of the first few moments where I don’t feel subpar to a 4-year college student. Standing here today, I felt seen not just as a student, but as a person who has proven their ability to succeed. I want you to feel the same way; you were hand-picked by someone who believes in you. Congrats.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Be Water</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/02/20/be-water.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be Water" /><published>2024-02-20T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-20T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/02/20/be-water</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/02/20/be-water.html">&lt;h2&gt; I. Popo (Grandmother) &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandmother came to America 60 years ago, her methods unclear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She knew some English, but had forgotten most of it since. She plays mahjong with her provincial association (同鄉會) friends, and she hates Panda Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popo never made it out of Chinatown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assimilation is a privilege for the rich and the powerful of her generation, she said. Those who were fresh off the boat with wealth and status go on to marry someone like Mitch McConnell or Sun Yat-Sen. The rest of us are all third-class citizens packed in little Chinatowns across America, hoping that their children or grandchildren would one day overcome that invisible fence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered what warrants such insecurity and self-hatred. Referencing the age-old argument, I replied, “If you hate it here so much, why don’t you just go back?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She replied, with slight disdain and disappointment, that I will never understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;II. “Just go back”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a child, my aunts took me to a fortune teller to read my &quot;Bazi&quot; (Eight Titles of Destiny). She told me that my life would resemble a winding stream: vast oceans merging into a flowing body of water, ambitious and imaginative, yet never remaining constant, never settling down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have known for most of my life that I was going to move to America after high school, but I did not have a clear idea of what that meant exactly. All I knew was that moving to a foreign country, specifically the West, is exciting and worth flaunting. That US Passport, or UK, or Canada, is your golden ticket to success. Classmates would have conversations about having family in Canada or planning to immigrate to the UK. My relatives told me that if I were a boy, Chinese “chicks” would run to marry me like flies to honey for that green card. And I knew that it was harder to immigrate to the US, so I would wear “Chinese-American” like a medal of honor. Immigrating is cool. Having foreign citizenship is cool. Being as far away as the idea of being Chinese is cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my perception of my Chinese-American identity before 2019. We Hongkongers pride ourselves on being colonized by the UK: we want the world to know that our adoptive mother was not an abusive commie, that our unique culture was bestowed upon us by Western civilization. I carry an average amount of internalized Sinophobia within me, that I don’t hate being Chinese, but I despise being associated with the PRC. I enjoyed studying Chinese history and ancient literature, but I never understood the significance of knowing them. All I knew was that China has always been a very backward and conservative country, and that Confucianism has poisoned our collective consciousness that the preference for sons over daughters pertains to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019, a protest movement in Hong Kong shook our faith. The incident resulted in tighter national security laws, and the US declaring Hong Kong no longer autonomous from the PRC. I thought I was immune from politics and the struggle for freedom; I was not. That was the last blow to the joy and pride we once owned, the last golden light of the fight for freedom coughed its way out, and the city fell into the Dark Ages. Leaving Hong Kong was no longer a boastful privilege, but an escape plan. Young Hongkongers with college degrees spent their life savings to work as cashiers and delivery drivers in London, parents who swear they love China rushed to send their kids overseas. I used to laugh and mock how silly that is, how white people must be laughing their asses off of how much we idolize the West. But now, it is just plain tragic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;大江東去，浪淘盡，千古風流人物。&lt;br&gt;
- 蘇軾 念奴嬌·赤壁懷古&lt;br&gt;
To the East Sea flows the Yangtze River,&lt;br&gt;
washing away forever, in tides of times,&lt;br&gt;
all the heroic souls of the past we remember.&lt;br&gt;
-So Shi, “Charm of a Maiden Singer”- Remembrance of the Tale of the Crimson Cliff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gatsby had a point. I spent the last couple of years boating against the current, chasing vestiges of my past. I held on to what I had lost, like double-decker buses and pineapple buns, longing for my high school years of triumph and glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, I learned about the historical weight of what it meant to be Chinese American. The combination of ethnicity and nationality paints the picture of diaspora: every immigrant carries a story of leaving their homeland and escaping political turmoil, a sentiment likely shared by Koreans and Vietnamese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;America is steeped in hypocrisy. The American Dream propagates the notion that hard work can lead to success, regardless of origins, under the condition of being white. America, a country built on stolen land, dares to judge who is worthy of being legal. The construction of America&apos;s largest railroad system, the very foundation of modern American trade, was built on the death and labor of thousands of Chinese workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue isn&apos;t about the ability to assimilate; it&apos;s about the worthiness of assimilation. Behind the term “Chinese American” is decades of courage and determination, to be recognized as Americans of Chinese descent and not just Chinks. The invisible fence was never about language, it was about the fight for our place at the American table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;III. Be Water&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, the ambition of &quot;making it, no matter what&quot; motivates millions of people to strive for a better life in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been to the Bruce Lee Memorial Museum twice. I was aware of his legacy as the first great Chinese American martial artist in the US, specifically the scene in a movie where he said the famous words, 「你地記住，中國人唔係東亞病夫！」(Let it be known, the Chinese are not the sick men of East Asia!). He garnered respect from both the East and West, becoming that bridge of culture before the age of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Lee had taken both Chinese and Western cultures and combined them into his distinctive vernacular. In archival footage of his interviews, I was taken aback by the distinctively Cantonese accent in his fluent English. His letters to home reflect his internal elegance, with his calligraphy resembling that of an elite white man, cursive twisting and swirling however he pleases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his famous interview, he explains his philosophy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Empty your mind, be formless. Shapeless, like water. If you put water into a cup, it becomes the cup. You put water into a bottle and it becomes the bottle. You put it in a teapot, it becomes the teapot. Now, water can flow or it can crash. Be water, my friend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He puts it so well. To be water: to adapt anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like millions of immigrants before and after me, this profound grief for my homeland fuels the resilience and strength that shapes my new identity with each passing ripple. I wish to be water, moving and bending with the currents, flowing with ease according to the shape of my surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;IV. Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lady I met at my apartment building asked if I could teach her daughter Cantonese. The girl, an eleven-year-old, could barely articulate to her grandparents. She disliked Chinese school, and would much prefer speaking in English and making her mother translate for her. I want to teach her more elementary, everyday phrases like “josun” and “nei sik jor fan mei”, hoping that Cantonese could impress her, and she would be able to impress her grandparents with these simple sentences. “Cantonese is a dying language,” I told her mother, “I hope Sophia would grow up being proud to be Cantonese and thank you for making her learn it some day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I come from a position of privilege. I was born right on time for the internet, where I get to learn the good ol’ American English from YouTubers and pirated movies. I was given by my Northern Chinese ancestors with the tall nose bridge, not to let strangers assume I’m Eurasian, but to conquer the cold weather of the North. My parents blessed me with 18 years of life in Hong Kong, so when I left Hong Kong, Hong Kong never left me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose that I have made it out of Chinatown. But I now understand what Popo meant. &lt;/p&gt;
Assimilation, pushing and pulling like tides, with one generation aspiring to be more American, and the next wishing to be less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be water, my friend.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I. Popo (Grandmother) My grandmother came to America 60 years ago, her methods unclear.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pondering on 2/14</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/02/14/pondering-on-2-14.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pondering on 2/14" /><published>2024-02-14T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-14T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/02/14/pondering-on-2-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2024/02/14/pondering-on-2-14.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey. It’s me. I took a hiatus from writing feminist think pieces for a while, mostly due to school. I barely had time to think about things like this because school was so overwhelming. But now that I have found some peace and time to myself, I would like to use 2/14 to talk about some opinions brewing in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to start off by talking about some certain things someone had said to me a while ago. It didn’t bother me back then, but it was haunting me in the back of my mind for a couple of months and I do want to talk about it. Essentially, somebody was crying over thinking they were dumber than me. In an effort to comfort them, a friend said they (the crying one) were smarter than me. Well that shit did hurt because I don’t understand why comment was needed in comforting that person at the expense of comparing our smartness. Mostly, I took offense because that person was literally not smarter in any way shape or form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that makes me ponder of me doing all this. I have so much confidence in my ability and my career that, other comments like “your ass is too flat” or “no man would ever love you” can hurt me. And yes, those two things were said to my face by a certain individual that, now that I regained clarity, realize how dumb and stupid it was. Those things cannot hurt me because they are not what I value. They don’t concern me. Nobody can pull me, so why would I care about pulling someone? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will admit that I have some sort of ego that I garnered from getting 4.0s and scholarships for 2 years straight, and I am aware that there is a lot of people smarter than me. I am being humbled by Berkeley as we speak, so I am by no means saying I am a genius or anything. But I pride myself for being balanced. I have always been balanced, the perfect balance in popularity and academics, in looks and brains, in extroversion and introversion, in masculinity and femininity. What thots don’t have, I have it. What nerds don’t have, I have it. So when I look back to my reputation and legacy, I want people to know that I am proud of my balance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had this talk with a certain immature and patriotic individual I knew back in high school (iykyk), which she explicitly told me that she is a very “masculine” person. Amused and invested, I asked why. She immediately clarified that she is not dysphoric or anything, which I had coming since she is very outwardly feminine and flashy. But she regards herself as a “masculine woman” because she does not align with feminine roles and, in her words, “women’s values”. She is a proud misogynist and believes that most women belong in the kitchen. “But you and I, of course, are not most women, so we are going to do greater things than the rest of them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I diagnosed her with “raging narcissist with immense insecurity and cognitive dissonance” right then and there. I understood where she was coming from, but I thought that her anger was misplaced. We could both agree that this was an unfair world and women do get the shorter end of the stick. We were both pick mes with bold aspirations, desperate for that “honorary son” title from our fathers. But at one point, our values diverged in being a misogynist vs. a misandrist. She wishes that she was born with a penis, while I do not; she regards her gender as an obstacle, while I see it as a source of courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is, I don’t hate men. If I really do hate men, I would not have tried so hard to invade men’s spaces and deal with them every single day. If I actually hate men, I would have become a English major and hang out with the girls and the gays every day. But I do hate the shackles that come with being a woman, as well as the audacity of men. Those are the two main things that drives me mad every day, it is just a lot more chonkier to say than “I hate m*n”. But m*n are placeholders for these things, they are complicit with wrapping the patriarchy with a nice bow. I don’t think I would have wanted to be a man, and I don’t put men on a pedestal. Being a m*n is the most embarrassing thing a person could do, so why would I wish that upon myself? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not my intention to make this whole message about myself. I do want all the ladies, especially the single girls to know that I am so proud of you. I am so proud of you for withstanding the stinky couples walking around. I am proud of you for surviving in this society that regards single people to be less than people in relationships. It such a shame that as civilized as our society pretends to be, we are still evaluating people’s worth by their matibility. That a woman could be smart and successful and still get asked “when are you getting married” or “why don’t you have a boyfriend”. We should not define people by who they are with (or not with). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is quite tragic, but to attention seek is human nature. And that yearning of romantic love, to be desired and wanted, is innate. It’s how we reproduce anyways. But I am on the belief that people wouldn’t fall in love if they have never heard of love. Platonic love and motherly love, sure, but romantic love? Nah fam I could be single for the rest of my life and I would not care. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Perhaps it is true that we do not really exist until there is someone there to see us existing, we cannot properly speak until there is someone who can understand what we are saying in essence, we are not wholly alive until we are loved.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;―Alain de Botton, On Love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I can acknowledge that love is an integral part of the human experience and most of us would not be here if everyone is as cynical as I am. Perhaps I will look back and read all of this just to find how bitter and embarrassing I am for writing and publishing this. But, until I find the piece of romantic love that people claim to be so life-changing. I don’t long for love, I long for the euphoria that comes with being in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this will be an ongoing experience for the foreseeable future. I do wish nothing but the best for the couples out there, for the singles longing for someone, and for those who have yet to find someone. Stay safe out there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Hey. It’s me. I took a hiatus from writing feminist think pieces for a while, mostly due to school. I barely had time to think about things like this because school was so overwhelming. But now that I have found some peace and time to myself, I would like to use 2/14 to talk about some opinions brewing in my head.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dear 20 Year Old Me</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/11/04/dear-20-year-old-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear 20 Year Old Me" /><published>2023-11-04T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-11-04T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/11/04/dear-20-year-old-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/11/04/dear-20-year-old-me.html">&lt;p&gt;I am turning 20 in a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, let me do this again with a bit more excitement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am turning 20 in a couple of days...! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth is, I am not overly excited about this supposed &quot;best decade of my life&quot;. I feel like the real challenge is coming ahead, and I&apos;m not too fond of it. I wished that people would take their time growing up, so I can take my time growing up; but unfortunately, 20 is that stage in life where you could probably no longer pretend to be young. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is terrible. I am a two-decade-old artifact. I was born twenty years ago. 2003 was twenty. years. ago. Can you believe that? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the day I turned ten. After dinner, I walked in front of my parents, crossing the King’s Road late at 10 pm, contemplating my age. “Now that you’re 10,” I thought to myself, “you might have experienced all the digit changes of your life. You might have one more if you’re lucky, but for most people, this is it.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it. That. was. it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that 10-year-old person would be proud of me for making it through this decade. The first half was a blur, god knows the things I’ve done that were confusing. But for the second half, you have accomplished a lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to say that my 19th year on this Earth was pretty good. Better than my 18th, I would say. There were a lot of things that I achieved over the past year, things that I would remember for the rest of my life (hopefully). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s go back to your identity problem. I used to wish that people understood more of my serious side than my goofy side. I wanted to kill the jester so people could take me more seriously. But, the truth is, I don&apos;t think it is possible. I am slowly realizing the part of me that&apos;s the jester, will always be in my blood. It is fortunately but also unfortunately an integral part of you. But the good news is, it is not that bad of a first impression. I think having this enthusiastic, approachable demeanor really draws people in. And people like you for that, so why can&apos;t you like yourself for that? Instead of focusing so much on the issues that your personality brings, can you instead change your expectations of how you want to be perceived? You want to be that mysterious, dark stranger that lures people in, but unfortunately, that will probably have to be your secondary personality from now on. Let’s not be that negative, trying-to-someone-else energy to the third decade of your life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not the party person, nor the lone wolf. You are not a big yo-dog, nor are you a weird-ass nerd. You are somewhere in between. And I think there is a lot more merit in that than you are leading yourself to believe. You are an enigma that you cannot decipher, and I hope you can come to terms with your perception of yourself, don&apos;t dwell in yesterday&apos;s glory and move on with your next chapter. I know you are in a bit of a transition right now, having not a particular passion in any particular subject outside of your career; if this continues, I do not doubt that you are going to turn into one of those people you despise the most. If you want to break the mold, you have got to break your rigid ideas of &quot;cool&quot;, &quot;cringe&quot;, and everything in between. You are too good at setting boundaries for others, but at one point I do think you have to work on your boundaries with yourself. Forgive yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pivoting to a whole different topic, I do want to set a new goal for 20-year-old me. As the beginning of the second decade of your life, I hope you can learn how to follow through. It is like the next chapter of &quot;starting that first draft&quot;: you know how much more you could accomplish if you follow through with your discipline and your goals. Stop being a sugar addict. Go to the gym. Apply for more gigs. Be more proactive in connecting with others. I know it&apos;s hard. But you need to move out of your comfort zone so you can grow. So you&apos;re not stuck inside the house listening to the same 3 songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing old will only get slower and sadder from now on. But there is light at the end of the tunnel. And I wish you the blastiest blast 20-year-old year and the overall start of the 3rd decade of your life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I am turning 20 in a couple of days.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Barbenheimer</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/08/09/on-barbenheimer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Barbenheimer" /><published>2023-08-09T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-09T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/08/09/on-barbenheimer</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/08/09/on-barbenheimer.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve thought about this long and hard. It was a difficult decision to make, but I knew the answer the entire time. a decision nobody asked for, not even Universal Pictures. But you&apos;re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew the answer the minute I finished Oppenheimer. it is, undoubtedly, the superior Barbenheimer film. And I really liked Barbie. But Oppenheimer made my chest pound so fast and I got very emotional towards the end I almost cried on a couple of occasions. It didn’t ask for sympathy or scorn for Oppenheimer’s character; it was a true introspection on humanity with the focal point on Dr. Oppenheimer. Humans harness tools that are too powerful for us to wield, and we suffer from consequences stemming from our inability to keep ourselves accountable. 3 hours of Cillian Murphy, cinematic tension, and moral ambiguity. Absolutely brilliant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love physics. to understand physics is to seek the beauty of matter, the intricacies of the universe. It truly asks you to revere whoever, or whatever made this world possible, the closest way for us to learn how all this came to be. but that, unfortunately, is not the case for Oppie. He created the deadliest weapon yet, thereby unveiling the ugliness of humanity. This is what happens when you put science into politics. He made the bomb. Now what? When did humans get so comfortable with wielding the power to destroy ourselves? Oppenheimer’s worst fear came true. He is death, the destroyer of worlds. But he knew that it would have been someone else if he hadn’t done it, and he naively believed that the US Government would only use the atomic bomb to threaten, not to destroy. The tragedy of Oppenheimer was that he didn’t build it with the intention to kill, but it was also his moral conscience that ultimately led to his downfall. Bro felt bad. Can’t patriots feel bad about killing their enemies? America is weird. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose that I will talk about Barbie for a bit too, since I named this one Barbenheimer. Well, I really enjoyed watching it. Ken was more than kenough and he absolutely stole the show. I loved the Kens while watching it, but now I find myself wishing that Barbie’s character is more developed. Her motivations for exploring death and depression were pretty forced, and nobody left the theater rooting for her. I felt like I was watching a watered-down Truman Show, and the audience simply can’t feel for Barbie. I can’t feel for her when she became human. America Ferreira’s monologue was good, but the placement of it felt a bit forced. A bit too on the nose as an empowering moment. I am sorry. The supposedly emotional moments did not deliver. In short, the Barbie movie’s strengths in comedy and set/ fashion design did not overcome the paper-thin plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, Barbenheimer has been a hell of a ride for cinephiles like me. They were absolute gems of the summer, and Universal Pictures really hit the jackpot with both of these films. Good job. Now, let&apos;s pay our writers and actors better so more good movies like Barbie and Oppenheimer can be made. Cool? Cool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I’ve thought about this long and hard. It was a difficult decision to make, but I knew the answer the entire time. a decision nobody asked for, not even Universal Pictures. But you&apos;re welcome.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Grace</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/06/05/grace.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grace" /><published>2023-06-05T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-05T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/06/05/grace</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/06/05/grace.html">&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia kills. That insatiable yearning for the good old days is the greatest lover and enemy of humanity. I do not regard myself as a particularly nostalgic person, but I have had bursts of flashbacks here and there. That one dark night, as the needle dropped to the soundtrack of my faltering youth, I strained my consciousness from the present and back to California. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who had never been to San Francisco, Chinatown is right next to Little Italy. I have always thought that their proximity was deliberate. I never did research on which came first, but I suppose that one must have wanted the other company in this strange, unfamiliar city. Both Chinese and Italian Americans must have been marginalized at one point. It is the common bond they share, the bond of trauma. Settling on the winding hills of San Francisco must have helped the immigrants overcome their loneliness all those years ago. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a Chinese proverb that goes, “Two tigers cannot share the same hill.” The Chinese and Italian mafia were at odds in their heyday. I remember watching a film, “The Year of the Dragon” in the cinemas down in Castro. It was 1985. The movie was set in New York City, but I resonated with the location of Little Italy and Chinatown in SF. Overthrowing mafia bosses, drug trading, and all kinds of shady businesses. It is like, loneliness breeds misery, and misery needs company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father owned the bakery on the street right between Chinatown and Little Italy back then. Although I had moved away for school at the ripe age of 20, I would go there from time to time to visit my parents. It happened on a cold night of Spring down in San Francisco, as I was about to go home for dinner with my parents. I turned the corner to Stockton with my car. Coit Tower cast its erected shadow upon the dimly lit streets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I went back home, and a lot has changed around here. A new café across from the bakery has caught my eye. It was Sicilian. I can’t remember the name now, but it was full of island-themed decorations. On the wall of the side hangs oversized posters of &lt;i&gt;Matrimonio all&apos;italiana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Divorzio all&apos;italiana&lt;/i&gt;. I do not recall seeing the latter, but I did recall seeing Sophia Loren’s ample bosom in the former. The decoration was alluringly suffocating, it was more Sicilian-tourist themed than Sicilian. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was strange that a café would open this late at 11 pm, but its warm golden light compelled me to look inside. I have grown accustomed to my solitude, and I didn’t want to see my folks anyway. There I was, walking into this empty cafe without any particular intent. I sat right next to the &lt;i&gt;Matrimonio all&apos;italiana&lt;/i&gt; poster, right beneath Loren’s gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I saw her. She passed me from the table swiftly, her shirt almost falling from her lean shoulder. I was too late to turn my head around to see her face, but I felt a slight gust of wind as she walked passed me. I caught a glimpse of her white skirt as it brushed against the side of my shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not know what I wanted going in. I was not hungry, and now I have to find an excuse to stay without looking like an asshole. She came out from the kitchen, this time with an apron around her waist. I looked up, and she looks back at me with her hands on the desk. I studied the expression on her face. It was the familiar emotion of tired bleakness from every waitress I had ever seen. She wasn’t particularly beautiful, but there was something unique about her face. She asked if I wanted to order anything. I knew three different Italian dishes, and I definitely do not want pizza or pasta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tiramisu, please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took the menu and left. I suppose that she is the only one working right now, so she also took up the roles of host, waitress, and cashier. I was scanning my surroundings, and there were a lot of intriguing things around me. I can’t remember it clearly now, but I believe that there were a few plants with heads as flower pots. The colorful porcelain eyes stare right back into mine.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music started playing in the café. I looked up and saw small stereo speakers around the cashier table, with a spinning CD inside, and there it was playing softly, Jeff Buckley’s “Corpus Christi Carol”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a sacred, haunting lullaby. Jeff Buckley’s falsettos were soft yet piercing, and echoing is the soft electric guitar that wanders through this crowded empty chamber. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She came out with the tiramisu. She placed it on the table and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song comes to a close, and I waited in anticipation for the next. If “Eternal Life” is next, that means she is playing the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soft guitar was traded for an aggressive, angry grunge riff. It was indeed, “Eternal Life”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buckley was influenced by Led Zepplin, more so than his father’s folk rock. The song forms a stark contrast from “Corpus Christi Carol”, and I adore the placement of the song here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wished to tell her how much I love this album. I must first find an excuse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I barely touched the tiramisu. I was engaged with the music, bopping my head to the harsh rhythm.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“When will I find the strength to bring me release? &lt;br&gt;Tell me where is the love in what your prophet has said.”&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br&gt; Buckley proposed furiously.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help but sing along. I believe that it might have caught her attention. She shuffled from her kitchen with a cup of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You listen to &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I do. Jeff Buckley was an amazing artist.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I know. It is like his ghost haunts me every time I hear his voice. It is a shame that he only made one album.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded as she took a sip from her cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a second to listen to the song.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“I love your voice and your dance insane &lt;br&gt;

I hear your words and I know your pain”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;“Extraordinary debut album,” I replied. “Sometimes I wonder if he hadn’t died so soon, would he make mediocre music and have a vastly different legacy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like the James Dean of his time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;i&gt;Exactly&lt;/i&gt; like the James Dean of his time.”&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I turned in the direction of her voice. Her body was leaning against the bar table, with the cup sitting on the edge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiled. “Are you not enjoying the tiramisu?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told her I wasn’t actually hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She offered a cup of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I replied. I liked where this was going, so I used that as an excuse to continue our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She came back with her cup and mine. I was caught off-guard by the strong aroma of the bite-sized cup of Italian espresso. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; She asked me if I wanted sugar. I declined. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Y’know, Italians do put sugar in their espressos.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I prefer the stripped-down version of things,” I responded, looking at her from above, unaware of the innuendo. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She chuckled lightly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, why didn’t I expect that from a Jeff Buckley listener?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You should’ve.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She sat across from me at the table. She was leaning towards my side, and I remember thinking that it meant that she wanted to further our conversation. She asked me which song was my favorite from &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forget Her” was playing. &lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;I told her, it was this one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told her about my story of how this song was almost tailor-made for me when I was 18. Looking back, my teenage heartbreak did not compare to the melancholia evoked in the song.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She swayed left and right to the slow rhythm of the song. She told me it was a nice one, but it wasn’t her favorite. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished my cup of espresso. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Which one is it?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have one in mind.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tell me about it.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She chuckled, her eyes wandering to the clock. I smiled and pleaded for her to tell me. It wasn’t fair that she knew my favorite song and I don’t know hers.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;It was “Lover, You Should’ve Come Over.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She got up, took my empty cup into hers, and told me to wait for the bill. I couldn’t help but grin at her answer. I thought she was hinting at something. She wasn’t, but I was hoping that she was. It was the song right before “Corpus Christi Carol” on the album. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She placed the tip tray on the table with a receipt. I put a $20 dollar bill on the tip tray, and she took it to the cashier&apos;s desk. My thoughts persisted in her direction. “Forget Her” was the last song on the album, so the disc would have been finished at that point.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read the “Thank you, Please Come Again” from the sign hanging on the door. But I didn’t want this to be over. I got up and walked towards where she was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hummed the tune of “Lover, You Should’ve Come Over”: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Maybe I’m too young

&lt;br&gt;To keep good love from going wrong
  
&lt;br&gt;But tonight you&apos;re on my mind”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked up. For a second, a rush of embarrassment and adrenaline came over me. This was the most ingratiating thing I have ever done, like a suitor singing from the balcony of a fair maiden. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anything, she should have walked away and pretended this never happened.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out with my hand over the counter, continuing my serenade in grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Too young to hold on

&lt;br&gt;And too old to just break free and run”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s my favorite lyric,” she responded to my plead with a slightly judgmental smirk.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I withdrew my hand, assuming that it was a rejection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out of the door, still singing the rest of the tune in my head. I did not dare to look back, wondering if Eurydice was ever going to spare a response. And I did not want to say goodbye, I’d never walk this street again. The street was freezing, I could see the vapor of my breath as I walked across the street.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I unlocked my car parked right next to my father’s store. The thinly frosted metal on the car proved how much time had passed as I spent time there. I looked back to the Sicilian Café, and I see the silhouette of her from the window. She was wearing a long, burgundy coat, with her back facing towards me. She held her hair from her neck with both hands, then adjusted its position to keep the strands on either side of her shoulder. I was still standing on the side of my car, eagerly waiting for a reply. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She dimmed the lights of the Café and walked out of place. Her eyes met mine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re tearing me apart!” I yelled across the street, giving my best shot of a James Dean impression.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t tell if she was rolling her eyes or smiling at me, but she turned her back to me once again and locked the door of the Café. I needed to think of something quick to get her attention. I looked over to either side of the street and walked towards her. I could feel my hands getting colder and colder. Yet, the audacity that I had at that moment overcame the freezing temperature. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before you ask, we already had coffee.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was just going to say that I have the Legacy Edition of &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt; at home if you’re interested,” I came up with this excuse right before I walked up to her. She was only a few inches shorter than me.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right, I’ve yet to hear that one yet.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You should’ve expected that from a Jeff Buckley listener,” I replied. We met an hour ago, and we already have our own little inside joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be honest, I do not recall the intricate details past this point. This was the story of how she and I met, and somehow we ended up at my place. I was too caught up in acting cool, and the truth is, I did not own the extended version of &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;. I saw it in a record store once, but I did not buy the record. I prayed to the Gods that she had never listened to the extended version, so I could carry on pretending that what I owned was, in fact, the extended version. I made sure to put the album on a loop, so this night could last forever. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night thickens. We spent our time together listening to &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;, from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Kiss me, please kiss me &lt;br&gt;
But kiss me out of desire, babe, not consolation &lt;br&gt;

Oh, you know it makes me so angry &lt;br&gt;

&apos;Cause I know that in time, I&apos;ll only make you cry &lt;br&gt;

This is our last goodbye&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every moment we touched, I was begging my record player to not malfunction so this would last for a while. Every song flew by, and I wished I had the extended version. I was getting to know her, getting to know every inch of her. My mind glitches every time our eyes met, wondering if it was all but a delicate fantasy. It was as if she had awakened something in me, something that had been dormant since I was eighteen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea when we winded down, but I remembered the last moments when I looked over at her sleeping, “Hallelujah” was playing. A beautiful rendition of the Leonard Cohen song, Jeff Buckley changed the gospel-styled song into a soft, melancholic ballad. I turned around to observe the subtle rise and fall of her chest as she breathes under the dim light. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“But remember, when I moved in you  &lt;br&gt;
And the holy dove was moving too &lt;br&gt;
And every breath we drew was Hallelujah”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That had always been my favorite part of the song. It reminds me of that moment. An eclectic mix of thoughts was at the back of my mind, but all I could focus on was that tranquility with the girl who loves &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;. Her silhouette echoes my lingering gaze. I was studying her ebbs and flows. I thought to myself, there was something asymmetrical about her body. The transition from her waist to her hips was just as peculiar. She was nothing like I have ever seen.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lump came to my throat, and I was ashamed of my voyeuristic impulses. My dimwitted ingenuity had put my mind at unease, and now I must pay for the price. I paused the record and fell asleep on the sofa, wishing that I had never thought of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was gone the next morning. She came and left without a trace, except for the spinning &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt; disc in the player. I don’t know her name, but I would like to think it might be Grace. I never liked how it ended, but I assumed that she liked how we ended. I rarely return to my father’s store afterwards, fearing that I would see her again and not knowing what to say. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew older, I realized that it is unwise to find a lover that shares your personal tastes. If you want to separate your individual personality from hers, it is wiser to find someone that you know you are not going to latch on to. I dated women that had vastly different passions and tastes in music from mine. Although I would try to withhold my judgments, I cannot help but feel superior with my objective subjectivity, and not even my wife is immune to my snobbishness. The only woman that I allowed to have the same opinion as me, was the girl that liked &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the album, I no longer feel the same adoration for it as I did in the past. Whether it was because of the events of that night, or my own fault for overplaying, I simply do not feel the same about that album over time. It was like an old friend that I haven’t heard from for decades. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was, until a few days ago, I discover a copy of &lt;i&gt;Sketches for My  Sweetheart The Drunk&lt;/i&gt; at a vintage record store. My old &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt; disc has already been severely scratched, so I thought it was about time to give Jeff Buckley’s posthumous sophomore album a listen. He was only 30 years old when he died of accidental drowning. The album had confirmed my assumptions: it was not as good as &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;, not nearly as good as &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, I still don’t know if she knew I lied about owning the extended version. Perhaps it didn’t matter: although &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;’s extended version has a second disc of studio outtakes from the album, it doesn’t have “Forget Her”. And if I can have anything in common with that, it would be that I haven’t either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HxfE6PJmGS8?start=126&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;Inspired by:
&lt;br&gt;An Assortment of Short Stories by Haruki Murakami
&lt;br&gt;One line from Taylor Swift’s Cornelia Street
&lt;br&gt;And, of course, Jeff Buckley’s Grace&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Nostalgia kills. That insatiable yearning for the good old days is the greatest lover and enemy of humanity. I do not regard myself as a particularly nostalgic person, but I have had bursts of flashbacks here and there. That one dark night, as the needle dropped to the soundtrack of my faltering youth, I strained my consciousness from the present and back to California.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leslie</title><link href="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/04/01/leslie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leslie" /><published>2023-04-01T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/04/01/leslie</id><content type="html" xml:base="inherownwrite.com/jekyll/update/2023/04/01/leslie.html">&lt;p&gt;哥哥張國榮 對於我黎講，代表一個我似曾相識、素未謀面嘅香港，一個值得懷念，值得寵愛嘅香港。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;要理解一個如Leslie一樣嘅artist，未必可以一次過聽曬佢個discography。由零開始，佢嘅佢80年代巔峰時期嘅歌，以差唔多粵劇腔所唱嘅《為你鍾情》、《Summer Romance ‘87》都係我入坑嘅作品。特別係我媽以前係屋企唱嘅“少女心事”，同埋我臨走之前去南丫島飲酒，坐係沙灘聽“風繼續吹”，都係對我黎講非常personal嘅歌。 雖然我未去過disco，唔知咩叫rave party， 但係我從佢嘅訪談、佢嘅歌詞中，彷彿睇到80s香港光輝大時代嘅縮影。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;哥哥第一首真正令我感到驚嘆嘅歌，應該係“風再起時”。當時應該係考完DSE冇幾耐，我搵佢最出名嘅幾首歌黎聽，然後發現呢首。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;我 浮沉了十數年&lt;br&gt;

在星空裡閃 帶著惘然&lt;br&gt;

請你容我別去前&lt;br&gt;

贈出這闕歌 來日某天再相見&lt;br&gt;

  -“風再起時”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我當時同呢首歌resonate到佢去加拿大又要走又唔捨得嘅cognitive dissonance，而呢首歌更加催使我去了解哥哥同佢嘅歌。“當年情” 同 “飛機師的風衣”都係我同期鍾意佢嘅作品。 佢唱快歌嘅時候靚仔到絕，舞台魅力max，而唱慢歌嘅時候把聲非常細膩、真摯，經常令我諗起佢《金枝玉葉》唱“追”嗰一幕。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;要講我最鍾意嘅era, 一定係《熱情演唱會》。佢回歸樂壇後三個album嘅artistry，絕對係香港前無古人後無來者。佢長頭髮又留鬚嘅造型， 同佢之前喺跨越97“紅”嘅高踭鞋跳舞，都係佢androgyny美感最靚最正嘅時候。佢係《熱情》裏面快歌串燒，通俗d黎講就是serving c*nt，白底牛仔造型又型又索，台風超正。我應該睇左《熱情》60次咁上下，個album返學聽、放學聽。佢 inspire 我挑戰beyond gender norms風格嘅fashion，唔怕別人眼光去做自己。佢呢個era嘅“路過蜻蜓”、“陪你倒數”同我最鍾意嘅“夢到內河”更加係反映到佢experiment嘅決心。邊個唔get《熱情》可以同我傾下，佢呢場演唱會應該係香港樂壇數一數二嘅視覺、聽覺享受。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;哥哥人美心善、多friend嘅事蹟聽得多，難怪香港人就對佢同梅姐兩個咁好、咁掛住佢地。我更加多謝佢為香港帶來LGBT嘅representation：佢係《家有囍事》、《霸王別姬》、《春光乍洩》嘅演出，證明佢唔單止係一個歌手同演員，佢係一個藝術家。我之前係twitter聽過：”true beauty is not shown, it is evoked.“ 佢嘅cultural contribution比邊個都多，香港唔會忘記佢帶俾我地嘅片刻美麗。佢嘅人格魅力，出自於佢對藝術嘅嗰份熱誠，猶如Icarus般嘅天之驕子；可惜佢可能為左追求完美、追求美麗而飛得太高，最後雙翼被太陽融化而跌下。佢為藝術而生，為藝術而犧牲。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;講咁多，其實最後並唔係想拋書包，我知道我距離做高le哥迷應該有排追。我追張國榮同追我其他偶像唔同，佢唔係我romanticize嘅對象，唔係我迷之瘋狂，來得快去得快嘅偶像。我要慢慢聽佢嘅歌，了解佢嘅過份美麗，從而搵出更多鍾意佢嘅原因。呢個4月1日，我身為03年尾出世嘅fan，雖然未見過哥哥、未見證過佢出碟、拍戲嘅時候，但係希望通過我對佢嘅敬佩、佢嘅寵愛，可以令係天堂嘅佢，知道佢對香港嘅貢獻。佢好多歌我聽過，更多歌我未聽過。我會繼續loop《紅》、《陪你倒數》同《大熱》，得閒就繼續從佢嘅discography發掘更多hidden gems。老實講，我唔係好捨得再聽更多我未聽過哥哥嘅歌，因為我知道，聽一首，就少一首“新歌”。總有一天我會聽完佢嘅歌、睇曬佢嘅戲，但係嗰日蒞臨之前，我知道我同佢無數fans一樣，願意今生約定他生再擁抱。。。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">哥哥張國榮 對於我黎講，代表一個我似曾相識、素未謀面嘅香港，一個值得懷念，值得寵愛嘅香港。</summary></entry></feed>