<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-31T13:10:44-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">In Her Own Write</title><subtitle>Eternal malaise of the soul.</subtitle><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><entry><title type="html">Dear 20 Year Old Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/11/04/dear-20-year-old-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear 20 Year Old Me" /><published>2023-11-04T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-11-04T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/11/04/dear-20-year-old-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/11/04/dear-20-year-old-me.html">&lt;p&gt;I am turning 20 in a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, let me do this again with a bit more excitement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am turning 20 in a couple of days...! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth is, I am not overly excited about this supposed &quot;best decade of my life&quot;. I feel like the real challenge is coming ahead, and I&apos;m not too fond of it. I wished that people would take their time growing up, so I can take my time growing up; but unfortunately, 20 is that stage in life where you could probably no longer pretend to be young. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is terrible. I am a two-decade-old artifact. I was born twenty years ago. 2003 was twenty. years. ago. Can you believe that? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the day I turned ten. After dinner, I walked in front of my parents, crossing the King’s Road late at 10 pm, contemplating my age. “Now that you’re 10,” I thought to myself, “you might have experienced all the digit changes of your life. You might have one more if you’re lucky, but for most people, this is it.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it. That. was. it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that 10-year-old person would be proud of me for making it through this decade. The first half was a blur, god knows the things I’ve done that were confusing. But for the second half, you have accomplished a lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to say that my 19th year on this Earth was pretty good. Better than my 18th, I would say. There were a lot of things that I achieved over the past year, things that I would remember for the rest of my life (hopefully). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s go back to your identity problem. I used to wish that people understood more of my serious side than my goofy side. I wanted to kill the jester so people could take me more seriously. But, the truth is, I don&apos;t think it is possible. I am slowly realizing the part of me that&apos;s the jester, will always be in my blood. It is fortunately but also unfortunately an integral part of you. But the good news is, it is not that bad of a first impression. I think having this enthusiastic, approachable demeanor really draws people in. And people like you for that, so why can&apos;t you like yourself for that? Instead of focusing so much on the issues that your personality brings, can you instead change your expectations of how you want to be perceived? You want to be that mysterious, dark stranger that lures people in, but unfortunately, that will probably have to be your secondary personality from now on. Let’s not be that negative, trying-to-someone-else energy to the third decade of your life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not the party person, nor the lone wolf. You are not a big yo-dog, nor are you a weird-ass nerd. You are somewhere in between. And I think there is a lot more merit in that than you are leading yourself to believe. You are an enigma that you cannot decipher, and I hope you can come to terms with your perception of yourself, don&apos;t dwell in yesterday&apos;s glory and move on with your next chapter. I know you are in a bit of a transition right now, having not a particular passion in any particular subject outside of your career; if this continues, I do not doubt that you are going to turn into one of those people you despise the most. If you want to break the mold, you have got to break your rigid ideas of &quot;cool&quot;, &quot;cringe&quot;, and everything in between. You are too good at setting boundaries for others, but at one point I do think you have to work on your boundaries with yourself. Forgive yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pivoting to a whole different topic, I do want to set a new goal for 20-year-old me. As the beginning of the second decade of your life, I hope you can learn how to follow through. It is like the next chapter of &quot;starting that first draft&quot;: you know how much more you could accomplish if you follow through with your discipline and your goals. Stop being a sugar addict. Go to the gym. Apply for more gigs. Be more proactive in connecting with others. I know it&apos;s hard. But you need to move out of your comfort zone so you can grow. So you&apos;re not stuck inside the house listening to the same 3 songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing old will only get slower and sadder from now on. But there is light at the end of the tunnel. And I wish you the blastiest blast 20-year-old year and the overall start of the 3rd decade of your life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I am turning 20 in a couple of days.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Barbenheimer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/08/09/on-barbenheimer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Barbenheimer" /><published>2023-08-09T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-09T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/08/09/on-barbenheimer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/08/09/on-barbenheimer.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve thought about this long and hard. It was a difficult decision to make, but I knew the answer the entire time. a decision nobody asked for, not even Universal Pictures. But you&apos;re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew the answer the minute I finished Oppenheimer. it is, undoubtedly, the superior Barbenheimer film. And I really liked Barbie. But Oppenheimer made my chest pound so fast and I got very emotional towards the end I almost cried on a couple of occasions. It didn’t ask for sympathy or scorn for Oppenheimer’s character; it was a true introspection on humanity with the focal point on Dr. Oppenheimer. Humans harness tools that are too powerful for us to wield, and we suffer from consequences stemming from our inability to keep ourselves accountable. 3 hours of Cillian Murphy, cinematic tension, and moral ambiguity. Absolutely brilliant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love physics. to understand physics is to seek the beauty of matter, the intricacies of the universe. It truly asks you to revere whoever, or whatever made this world possible, the closest way for us to learn how all this came to be. but that, unfortunately, is not the case for Oppie. He created the deadliest weapon yet, thereby unveiling the ugliness of humanity. This is what happens when you put science into politics. He made the bomb. Now what? When did humans get so comfortable with wielding the power to destroy ourselves? Oppenheimer’s worst fear came true. He is death, the destroyer of worlds. But he knew that it would have been someone else if he hadn’t done it, and he naively believed that the US Government would only use the atomic bomb to threaten, not to destroy. The tragedy of Oppenheimer was that he didn’t build it with the intention to kill, but it was also his moral conscience that ultimately led to his downfall. Bro felt bad. Can’t patriots feel bad about killing their enemies? America is weird. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose that I will talk about Barbie for a bit too, since I named this one Barbenheimer. Well, I really enjoyed watching it. Ken was more than kenough and he absolutely stole the show. I loved the Kens while watching it, but now I find myself wishing that Barbie’s character is more developed. Her motivations for exploring death and depression were pretty forced, and nobody left the theater rooting for her. I felt like I was watching a watered-down Truman Show, and the audience simply can’t feel for Barbie. I can’t feel for her when she became human. America Ferreira’s monologue was good, but the placement of it felt a bit forced. A bit too on the nose as an empowering moment. I am sorry. The supposedly emotional moments did not deliver. In short, the Barbie movie’s strengths in comedy and set/ fashion design did not overcome the paper-thin plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, Barbenheimer has been a hell of a ride for cinephiles like me. They were absolute gems of the summer, and Universal Pictures really hit the jackpot with both of these films. Good job. Now, let&apos;s pay our writers and actors better so more good movies like Barbie and Oppenheimer can be made. Cool? Cool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I’ve thought about this long and hard. It was a difficult decision to make, but I knew the answer the entire time. a decision nobody asked for, not even Universal Pictures. But you&apos;re welcome.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Grace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/06/05/grace.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grace" /><published>2023-06-05T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-05T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/06/05/grace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/06/05/grace.html">&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia kills. That insatiable yearning for the good old days is the greatest lover and enemy of humanity. I do not regard myself as a particularly nostalgic person, but I have had bursts of flashbacks here and there. That one dark night, as the needle dropped to the soundtrack of my faltering youth, I strained my consciousness from the present and back to California. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who had never been to San Francisco, Chinatown is right next to Little Italy. I have always thought that their proximity was deliberate. I never did research on which came first, but I suppose that one must have wanted the other company in this strange, unfamiliar city. Both Chinese and Italian Americans must have been marginalized at one point. It is the common bond they share, the bond of trauma. Settling on the winding hills of San Francisco must have helped the immigrants overcome their loneliness all those years ago. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a Chinese proverb that goes, “Two tigers cannot share the same hill.” The Chinese and Italian mafia were at odds in their heyday. I remember watching a film, “The Year of the Dragon” in the cinemas down in Castro. It was 1985. The movie was set in New York City, but I resonated with the location of Little Italy and Chinatown in SF. Overthrowing mafia bosses, drug trading, and all kinds of shady businesses. It is like, loneliness breeds misery, and misery needs company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father owned the bakery on the street right between Chinatown and Little Italy back then. Although I had moved away for school at the ripe age of 20, I would go there from time to time to visit my parents. It happened on a cold night of Spring down in San Francisco, as I was about to go home for dinner with my parents. I turned the corner to Stockton with my car. Coit Tower cast its erected shadow upon the dimly lit streets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I went back home, and a lot has changed around here. A new café across from the bakery has caught my eye. It was Sicilian. I can’t remember the name now, but it was full of island-themed decorations. On the wall of the side hangs oversized posters of &lt;i&gt;Matrimonio all&apos;italiana&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Divorzio all&apos;italiana&lt;/i&gt;. I do not recall seeing the latter, but I did recall seeing Sophia Loren’s ample bosom in the former. The decoration was alluringly suffocating, it was more Sicilian-tourist themed than Sicilian. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was strange that a café would open this late at 11 pm, but its warm golden light compelled me to look inside. I have grown accustomed to my solitude, and I didn’t want to see my folks anyway. There I was, walking into this empty cafe without any particular intent. I sat right next to the &lt;i&gt;Matrimonio all&apos;italiana&lt;/i&gt; poster, right beneath Loren’s gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I saw her. She passed me from the table swiftly, her shirt almost falling from her lean shoulder. I was too late to turn my head around to see her face, but I felt a slight gust of wind as she walked passed me. I caught a glimpse of her white skirt as it brushed against the side of my shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not know what I wanted going in. I was not hungry, and now I have to find an excuse to stay without looking like an asshole. She came out from the kitchen, this time with an apron around her waist. I looked up, and she looks back at me with her hands on the desk. I studied the expression on her face. It was the familiar emotion of tired bleakness from every waitress I had ever seen. She wasn’t particularly beautiful, but there was something unique about her face. She asked if I wanted to order anything. I knew three different Italian dishes, and I definitely do not want pizza or pasta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tiramisu, please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took the menu and left. I suppose that she is the only one working right now, so she also took up the roles of host, waitress, and cashier. I was scanning my surroundings, and there were a lot of intriguing things around me. I can’t remember it clearly now, but I believe that there were a few plants with heads as flower pots. The colorful porcelain eyes stare right back into mine.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music started playing in the café. I looked up and saw small stereo speakers around the cashier table, with a spinning CD inside, and there it was playing softly, Jeff Buckley’s “Corpus Christi Carol”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a sacred, haunting lullaby. Jeff Buckley’s falsettos were soft yet piercing, and echoing is the soft electric guitar that wanders through this crowded empty chamber. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She came out with the tiramisu. She placed it on the table and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song comes to a close, and I waited in anticipation for the next. If “Eternal Life” is next, that means she is playing the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soft guitar was traded for an aggressive, angry grunge riff. It was indeed, “Eternal Life”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buckley was influenced by Led Zepplin, more so than his father’s folk rock. The song forms a stark contrast from “Corpus Christi Carol”, and I adore the placement of the song here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wished to tell her how much I love this album. I must first find an excuse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I barely touched the tiramisu. I was engaged with the music, bopping my head to the harsh rhythm.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“When will I find the strength to bring me release? &lt;br&gt;Tell me where is the love in what your prophet has said.”&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br&gt; Buckley proposed furiously.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help but sing along. I believe that it might have caught her attention. She shuffled from her kitchen with a cup of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You listen to &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I do. Jeff Buckley was an amazing artist.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I know. It is like his ghost haunts me every time I hear his voice. It is a shame that he only made one album.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded as she took a sip from her cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a second to listen to the song.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“I love your voice and your dance insane &lt;br&gt;

I hear your words and I know your pain”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;“Extraordinary debut album,” I replied. “Sometimes I wonder if he hadn’t died so soon, would he make mediocre music and have a vastly different legacy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like the James Dean of his time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;i&gt;Exactly&lt;/i&gt; like the James Dean of his time.”&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I turned in the direction of her voice. Her body was leaning against the bar table, with the cup sitting on the edge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiled. “Are you not enjoying the tiramisu?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told her I wasn’t actually hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She offered a cup of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I replied. I liked where this was going, so I used that as an excuse to continue our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She came back with her cup and mine. I was caught off-guard by the strong aroma of the bite-sized cup of Italian espresso. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; She asked me if I wanted sugar. I declined. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Y’know, Italians do put sugar in their espressos.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I prefer the stripped-down version of things,” I responded, looking at her from above, unaware of the innuendo. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She chuckled lightly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, why didn’t I expect that from a Jeff Buckley listener?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You should’ve.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She sat across from me at the table. She was leaning towards my side, and I remember thinking that it meant that she wanted to further our conversation. She asked me which song was my favorite from &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forget Her” was playing. &lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;I told her, it was this one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told her about my story of how this song was almost tailor-made for me when I was 18. Looking back, my teenage heartbreak did not compare to the melancholia evoked in the song.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She swayed left and right to the slow rhythm of the song. She told me it was a nice one, but it wasn’t her favorite. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished my cup of espresso. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Which one is it?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have one in mind.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tell me about it.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She chuckled, her eyes wandering to the clock. I smiled and pleaded for her to tell me. It wasn’t fair that she knew my favorite song and I don’t know hers.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;It was “Lover, You Should’ve Come Over.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She got up, took my empty cup into hers, and told me to wait for the bill. I couldn’t help but grin at her answer. I thought she was hinting at something. She wasn’t, but I was hoping that she was. It was the song right before “Corpus Christi Carol” on the album. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She placed the tip tray on the table with a receipt. I put a $20 dollar bill on the tip tray, and she took it to the cashier&apos;s desk. My thoughts persisted in her direction. “Forget Her” was the last song on the album, so the disc would have been finished at that point.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read the “Thank you, Please Come Again” from the sign hanging on the door. But I didn’t want this to be over. I got up and walked towards where she was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hummed the tune of “Lover, You Should’ve Come Over”: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Maybe I’m too young

&lt;br&gt;To keep good love from going wrong
  
&lt;br&gt;But tonight you&apos;re on my mind”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked up. For a second, a rush of embarrassment and adrenaline came over me. This was the most ingratiating thing I have ever done, like a suitor singing from the balcony of a fair maiden. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anything, she should have walked away and pretended this never happened.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out with my hand over the counter, continuing my serenade in grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Too young to hold on

&lt;br&gt;And too old to just break free and run”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s my favorite lyric,” she responded to my plead with a slightly judgmental smirk.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I withdrew my hand, assuming that it was a rejection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out of the door, still singing the rest of the tune in my head. I did not dare to look back, wondering if Eurydice was ever going to spare a response. And I did not want to say goodbye, I’d never walk this street again. The street was freezing, I could see the vapor of my breath as I walked across the street.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I unlocked my car parked right next to my father’s store. The thinly frosted metal on the car proved how much time had passed as I spent time there. I looked back to the Sicilian Café, and I see the silhouette of her from the window. She was wearing a long, burgundy coat, with her back facing towards me. She held her hair from her neck with both hands, then adjusted its position to keep the strands on either side of her shoulder. I was still standing on the side of my car, eagerly waiting for a reply. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She dimmed the lights of the Café and walked out of place. Her eyes met mine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re tearing me apart!” I yelled across the street, giving my best shot of a James Dean impression.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t tell if she was rolling her eyes or smiling at me, but she turned her back to me once again and locked the door of the Café. I needed to think of something quick to get her attention. I looked over to either side of the street and walked towards her. I could feel my hands getting colder and colder. Yet, the audacity that I had at that moment overcame the freezing temperature. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before you ask, we already had coffee.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was just going to say that I have the Legacy Edition of &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt; at home if you’re interested,” I came up with this excuse right before I walked up to her. She was only a few inches shorter than me.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right, I’ve yet to hear that one yet.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You should’ve expected that from a Jeff Buckley listener,” I replied. We met an hour ago, and we already have our own little inside joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be honest, I do not recall the intricate details past this point. This was the story of how she and I met, and somehow we ended up at my place. I was too caught up in acting cool, and the truth is, I did not own the extended version of &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;. I saw it in a record store once, but I did not buy the record. I prayed to the Gods that she had never listened to the extended version, so I could carry on pretending that what I owned was, in fact, the extended version. I made sure to put the album on a loop, so this night could last forever. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night thickens. We spent our time together listening to &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;, from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Kiss me, please kiss me &lt;br&gt;
But kiss me out of desire, babe, not consolation &lt;br&gt;

Oh, you know it makes me so angry &lt;br&gt;

&apos;Cause I know that in time, I&apos;ll only make you cry &lt;br&gt;

This is our last goodbye&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every moment we touched, I was begging my record player to not malfunction so this would last for a while. Every song flew by, and I wished I had the extended version. I was getting to know her, getting to know every inch of her. My mind glitches every time our eyes met, wondering if it was all but a delicate fantasy. It was as if she had awakened something in me, something that had been dormant since I was eighteen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea when we winded down, but I remembered the last moments when I looked over at her sleeping, “Hallelujah” was playing. A beautiful rendition of the Leonard Cohen song, Jeff Buckley changed the gospel-styled song into a soft, melancholic ballad. I turned around to observe the subtle rise and fall of her chest as she breathes under the dim light. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“But remember, when I moved in you  &lt;br&gt;
And the holy dove was moving too &lt;br&gt;
And every breath we drew was Hallelujah”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That had always been my favorite part of the song. It reminds me of that moment. An eclectic mix of thoughts was at the back of my mind, but all I could focus on was that tranquility with the girl who loves &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;. Her silhouette echoes my lingering gaze. I was studying her ebbs and flows. I thought to myself, there was something asymmetrical about her body. The transition from her waist to her hips was just as peculiar. She was nothing like I have ever seen.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lump came to my throat, and I was ashamed of my voyeuristic impulses. My dimwitted ingenuity had put my mind at unease, and now I must pay for the price. I paused the record and fell asleep on the sofa, wishing that I had never thought of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was gone the next morning. She came and left without a trace, except for the spinning &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt; disc in the player. I don’t know her name, but I would like to think it might be Grace. I never liked how it ended, but I assumed that she liked how we ended. I rarely return to my father’s store afterwards, fearing that I would see her again and not knowing what to say. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew older, I realized that it is unwise to find a lover that shares your personal tastes. If you want to separate your individual personality from hers, it is wiser to find someone that you know you are not going to latch on to. I dated women that had vastly different passions and tastes in music from mine. Although I would try to withhold my judgments, I cannot help but feel superior with my objective subjectivity, and not even my wife is immune to my snobbishness. The only woman that I allowed to have the same opinion as me, was the girl that liked &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the album, I no longer feel the same adoration for it as I did in the past. Whether it was because of the events of that night, or my own fault for overplaying, I simply do not feel the same about that album over time. It was like an old friend that I haven’t heard from for decades. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was, until a few days ago, I discover a copy of &lt;i&gt;Sketches for My  Sweetheart The Drunk&lt;/i&gt; at a vintage record store. My old &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt; disc has already been severely scratched, so I thought it was about time to give Jeff Buckley’s posthumous sophomore album a listen. He was only 30 years old when he died of accidental drowning. The album had confirmed my assumptions: it was not as good as &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;, not nearly as good as &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, I still don’t know if she knew I lied about owning the extended version. Perhaps it didn’t matter: although &lt;i&gt;Grace&lt;/i&gt;’s extended version has a second disc of studio outtakes from the album, it doesn’t have “Forget Her”. And if I can have anything in common with that, it would be that I haven’t either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HxfE6PJmGS8?start=126&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;Inspired by:
&lt;br&gt;An Assortment of Short Stories by Haruki Murakami
&lt;br&gt;One line from Taylor Swift’s Cornelia Street
&lt;br&gt;And, of course, Jeff Buckley’s Grace&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Nostalgia kills. That insatiable yearning for the good old days is the greatest lover and enemy of humanity. I do not regard myself as a particularly nostalgic person, but I have had bursts of flashbacks here and there. That one dark night, as the needle dropped to the soundtrack of my faltering youth, I strained my consciousness from the present and back to California.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leslie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/04/01/leslie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leslie" /><published>2023-04-01T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/04/01/leslie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/04/01/leslie.html">&lt;p&gt;哥哥張國榮 對於我黎講，代表一個我似曾相識、素未謀面嘅香港，一個值得懷念，值得寵愛嘅香港。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;要理解一個如Leslie一樣嘅artist，未必可以一次過聽曬佢個discography。由零開始，佢嘅佢80年代巔峰時期嘅歌，以差唔多粵劇腔所唱嘅《為你鍾情》、《Summer Romance ‘87》都係我入坑嘅作品。特別係我媽以前係屋企唱嘅“少女心事”，同埋我臨走之前去南丫島飲酒，坐係沙灘聽“風繼續吹”，都係對我黎講非常personal嘅歌。 雖然我未去過disco，唔知咩叫rave party， 但係我從佢嘅訪談、佢嘅歌詞中，彷彿睇到80s香港光輝大時代嘅縮影。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;哥哥第一首真正令我感到驚嘆嘅歌，應該係“風再起時”。當時應該係考完DSE冇幾耐，我搵佢最出名嘅幾首歌黎聽，然後發現呢首。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;我 浮沉了十數年&lt;br&gt;

在星空裡閃 帶著惘然&lt;br&gt;

請你容我別去前&lt;br&gt;

贈出這闕歌 來日某天再相見&lt;br&gt;

  -“風再起時”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我當時同呢首歌resonate到佢去加拿大又要走又唔捨得嘅cognitive dissonance，而呢首歌更加催使我去了解哥哥同佢嘅歌。“當年情” 同 “飛機師的風衣”都係我同期鍾意佢嘅作品。 佢唱快歌嘅時候靚仔到絕，舞台魅力max，而唱慢歌嘅時候把聲非常細膩、真摯，經常令我諗起佢《金枝玉葉》唱“追”嗰一幕。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;要講我最鍾意嘅era, 一定係《熱情演唱會》。佢回歸樂壇後三個album嘅artistry，絕對係香港前無古人後無來者。佢長頭髮又留鬚嘅造型， 同佢之前喺跨越97“紅”嘅高踭鞋跳舞，都係佢androgyny美感最靚最正嘅時候。佢係《熱情》裏面快歌串燒，通俗d黎講就是serving c*nt，白底牛仔造型又型又索，台風超正。我應該睇左《熱情》60次咁上下，個album返學聽、放學聽。佢 inspire 我挑戰beyond gender norms風格嘅fashion，唔怕別人眼光去做自己。佢呢個era嘅“路過蜻蜓”、“陪你倒數”同我最鍾意嘅“夢到內河”更加係反映到佢experiment嘅決心。邊個唔get《熱情》可以同我傾下，佢呢場演唱會應該係香港樂壇數一數二嘅視覺、聽覺享受。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;哥哥人美心善、多friend嘅事蹟聽得多，難怪香港人就對佢同梅姐兩個咁好、咁掛住佢地。我更加多謝佢為香港帶來LGBT嘅representation：佢係《家有囍事》、《霸王別姬》、《春光乍洩》嘅演出，證明佢唔單止係一個歌手同演員，佢係一個藝術家。我之前係twitter聽過：”true beauty is not shown, it is evoked.“ 佢嘅cultural contribution比邊個都多，香港唔會忘記佢帶俾我地嘅片刻美麗。佢嘅人格魅力，出自於佢對藝術嘅嗰份熱誠，猶如Icarus般嘅天之驕子；可惜佢可能為左追求完美、追求美麗而飛得太高，最後雙翼被太陽融化而跌下。佢為藝術而生，為藝術而犧牲。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;講咁多，其實最後並唔係想拋書包，我知道我距離做高le哥迷應該有排追。我追張國榮同追我其他偶像唔同，佢唔係我romanticize嘅對象，唔係我迷之瘋狂，來得快去得快嘅偶像。我要慢慢聽佢嘅歌，了解佢嘅過份美麗，從而搵出更多鍾意佢嘅原因。呢個4月1日，我身為03年尾出世嘅fan，雖然未見過哥哥、未見證過佢出碟、拍戲嘅時候，但係希望通過我對佢嘅敬佩、佢嘅寵愛，可以令係天堂嘅佢，知道佢對香港嘅貢獻。佢好多歌我聽過，更多歌我未聽過。我會繼續loop《紅》、《陪你倒數》同《大熱》，得閒就繼續從佢嘅discography發掘更多hidden gems。老實講，我唔係好捨得再聽更多我未聽過哥哥嘅歌，因為我知道，聽一首，就少一首“新歌”。總有一天我會聽完佢嘅歌、睇曬佢嘅戲，但係嗰日蒞臨之前，我知道我同佢無數fans一樣，願意今生約定他生再擁抱。。。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">哥哥張國榮 對於我黎講，代表一個我似曾相識、素未謀面嘅香港，一個值得懷念，值得寵愛嘅香港。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Give My Regards to Hong Kong</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/20/give-my-regards-to-hk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Give My Regards to Hong Kong" /><published>2023-01-20T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-20T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/20/give-my-regards-to-hk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/01/20/give-my-regards-to-hk.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Written in 2021? I think. Before the National Security Law, at least.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was seven years old, I moved across the Victoria Harbour of Hong Kong. It marked a significant change in my life, as my memories metamorphosed from blurry make-believe to lucid scenes. Though it takes only half an hour to go from Tsim Sha Tsui to North Point, it felt like oceans apart. Ten years later, I went back to the very neighborhood I once grew up in, and everything looks surprisingly foreign to me. I recall going to the local “wet market” with my mom, being petrified of the fish laying half-dead on ice, observing my mother’s bargain with the hawker; the market was bulldozed and reconstructed into a Best Western. Old local bookstores I once adored are now designer flagship stores, Beijing dumplings revamped into Korean barbecue restaurants... I felt utterly betrayed by this place, it is not the neighborhood I grew up in. The old building attendant at my old place didn’t even recognize me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong’s conflict of identity mirrors my own, it shaped me as an intrinsic paradox: the contradictory clash between the East and the West, the old and the new. Some of our streets are named “Prince Edward Road West”, the others “Tsat Tsz Mui Road” (the Road of the Seven Sisters). The Chinese value tradition, and our societal values are conservative, oftentimes limiting. However, Hong Kong is never the place to conform. We take pride in our freedom and democracy, characterized by British governance. As a post-handover child, I never experienced what happened before, but I grew up with the repercussions of the incident. I witnessed the change around me, not just the buildings, but the language, and the people... Hong Kong is at a crossroads with its character, and it has yet to decide what it wants to become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took time to reflect silently on my way back home. Hong Kong has faced a lot of challenges these years: The protests awakened the city, the pandemic shaken our faith, and God only knows what’s more to come. I have been the silent watcher, the judgmental scorner, and the idealistic revolutionary. Who am I to celebrate your triumphant odes? Who am I to weep for your downfall? I am powerless against the sands of time, I cannot do anything to stop these changes from happening. It takes courage to embrace change, change that sometimes we did not ask for. My hypocrisy was tomfoolery: it never occurred to me that as I departed Tsim Sha Tsui, Tsim Sha Tsui left me too. It slipped away before I even noticed, before I could put my feelings into words. How could I expect the attendant to recognize the seventeen-year-old before him, when I left at seven? I have always been changing, time will tell when wrinkles start to appear. For I am forever restless, I must mature from my one-sided perception of Hong Kong. I realized how similar we are at our cores, and I feel a sense of guilt with how long it took me to understand that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I am moving across the Pacific Ocean, I regard my coming-of-age sentiment toward Hong Kong as my parting gift to her. I can truly embrace my inner irony now, just like Hong Kong&apos;s journey toward self-actualization. The future is uncertain, but I know if you find your voice and stay authentic, I will appreciate you for who you are. Not the cyberpunk Pearl of the Orient Hollywood movies made you out to be, not the chaotic city of protests you were portrayed on news, but the Hong Kong I once knew, the Hong Kong I once adored. And you will do the same for me. Give my regards to Hong Kong, please don’t ever change, don’t stay the same either. I promise to stay passionate and genuine; I’ll leave Hong Kong far behind me, the city I once claimed as my own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Written in 2021? I think. Before the National Security Law, at least.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ricochet of Rejection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/26/ricochet-of-rejection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ricochet of Rejection" /><published>2022-11-26T23:13:50-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-26T23:13:50-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/26/ricochet-of-rejection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/26/ricochet-of-rejection.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; Or, alternatively, the logical explanation of illogical sentimentalists overthinking about the fear of rejections from others. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel bad for saying no to things. Whether it is ice cream, studying in the library, parties, or sleepovers, I often second-guess my decision when I know in my gut that I made the right choice. This has something to do with FOMO, perhaps, for the road not taken often looks more attractive than reality. We just have to negotiate with ourselves that life is made out of good and bad choices, and that’s what makes us human. What would other people think of you when you say “no”? Would your rejection hurt others? Well, if we are not sugarcoating things, then yes. It will hurt people, but if you did the math right, then it should only be temporary. Hurt and grief will pass, but mistakes and regrets often last. If you know that person well and they understand where you are coming from, this should not damage them permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women are socialized to say yes. You don’t want to offend anyone by spreading negativity, the virtue of being “agreeable”, by itself, implies that women should be pleasant creatures that offer nothing but peace and happiness for others to enjoy. In fact, when you think of the mechanism of a marriage proposal, the man is literally putting societal pressure upon a woman, who, partially due to the swept-away-at-the-moment phenomenon, gets lightheaded and say “yes”, so the guy on one knee would be able to stand up and put a leash onto the woman’s finger that would probably chain her forever, disguised as a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woah, all of this sounds like I just rejected somebody’s marriage proposal or something. No, I’m just trying to rewire my brain by recounting the things I have done and the choices I have made in the past. Perhaps you said no to something, and it somehow backfired or it made you left wondering what could have been. I wrote 2 years ago, “As long as you stay blissfully imaginative, anything could happen on the other side.” The beauty of keeping that Pandora’s Box forever locked is that you could make up anything in your head. If there is no objective truth to what could have happened, and no objectively correct way of doing things, then there would be no need to churn those sorrowful thoughts over and over again in your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; If you prefer the more sentimental way of thinking ways, may I offer you the concept of fate? If something (or someONE hmm) is really meant to be, they will come back to you, or you will go back to them. Just like Elizabeth Bennet and Mr. Darcy. Elizabeth spent days and nights regretting her rejection of Darcy’s proposal, but fate brought them back together and Darcy made things right this time. However, you look at couples like Laurie and Jo, fate did not bring the two back together because they were probably not “meant to be”. Jo’s rejection of Laurie did not make any sense to Laurie or the hopeless romantic reader back then (including me), but as I got older and started having ideas and goals similar to Jo’s, I understood why Jo made her decision and let Laurie go. This is how fate works, at least according to my fellow female writers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Y’know, one day, when you look back to all those things you have done that made you wind up here, you will realize that your choice meant very little to the grand scheme of things. Don’t lock yourself in the cell of regret and failure. That ice cream you didn’t eat, that sleepover you didn’t go to, that guy you didn’t date… one bad decision doesn’t alter lives, but a hundred bad decisions accumulate to form an avalanche of regrets. Don’t build your life around things you didn’t do, build it based on things you’ve done and the things you will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;We eat and we drink, we feel and we think&lt;br&gt;Far down the street we stray&lt;br&gt;I laugh and I cry and I&apos;m haunted by&lt;br&gt;Things I never meant nor wished to say&lt;br&gt;The midnight rain follows the train&lt;br&gt;We all wear the same thorny crown&lt;br&gt;Soul to soul, our shadows roll&lt;br&gt;And I&apos;ll be with you when the deal goes down&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bob Dylan, &lt;i&gt;“When the Deal Goes Down”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Or, alternatively, the logical explanation of illogical sentimentalists overthinking about the fear of rejections from others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Booksmart vs. Streetsmart</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/25/booksmart-vs-streetsmart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Booksmart vs. Streetsmart" /><published>2022-11-25T23:13:50-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-25T23:13:50-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/25/booksmart-vs-streetsmart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/25/booksmart-vs-streetsmart.html">&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I have always considered myself a streetsmart person over a booksmart person. I was so egotistic, that I even looked down upon people that I deemed as “nerds”, aka boring people who get good grades and have virtually no personality. Booksmart is about grades (in the books), while streetsmart is about the way of life (on the streets). I did not think about the consequences of getting Cs, the most important thing in life is to crack people up with my “quick-wittedness”, y’know how teenagers roll. Peer validation was the only form of validation that matters. And so, streetsmart became the sort of branding I gave myself: I may not get the highest grades in class, but I will vouch for the happiness people’s laughter/ approval could bring me. That was my goal, I was better than the nerds because I am wittier and better at socializing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, until recently, my perspective has changed gradually but fundamentally. I don’t know if this is maturity or career-planning-ground-control-to-major-roni, but I have come to the partial conclusion that booksmart would actually get you further in life than streetsmarts. Or, alternatively, both must be incorporated into a person in order for them to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of the difference between cleverness, smartness, intelligence, and wisdom? After a little contemplation and introspective reflection, I have deduced the formulas for these measures of mental ability: &lt;br&gt;Smartness: 10% of Streetsmart + 20% Booksmart = 30%&lt;br&gt;Cleverness: 20% Streetsmart + 30% Booksmart = 50%&lt;br&gt;Intelligence: 20% Streetsmart + 60% Booksmart = 80%&lt;br&gt;Wisdom: 30% Streetsmart + 120% Booksmart = 150%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Streetsmart comes from intuitive experiences, while booksmart accumulates from knowledge and philosophy. When I was a kid, I thought of myself as streetsmart because of my quick-wittedness and the fables I heard from people about “big life lessons”. I thought I knew everything without doing anything. I guess I was smart, but I was not intelligent. And in fact, being arrogant and boastful blocked people like me from ever reaching that other 50% of booksmart potential, which subsequently hinders the amount of knowledge I was able to accumulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Streetsmart can only get you so far in life. It is a boost for your abilities indeed, and I can’t really show you ways to “gain” streetsmart. You would know how to manipulate, strategize, and use logic to destroy your mortal enemies. These are only the essential skills of a businessman or a  mafia boss, but not of a successful or happy person in general. After all these years of glorifying streetsmarts, I now personally look down upon people that wield that as their sole skill. Streetsmarts cap at about 20% of your “smartness”, but it would not make up for the rest of the hard work you need to put in. Not to mention, none of us have the “maximum” amount of streetsmarts. There will always be people that are effortlessly smarter than you, and there is nothing you can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, there is something you can do: become booksmart. You may lose the battle of streetsmarts, but know that the war of booksmarts has barely begun. The beauty of being booksmart lies in the fairness of its game: you just got to work hard. Call me delusion or whatever, but now that I am in the land of the free and the home of the brave, I irrevocably believe that working hard will get you far in life. Soaking yourself in the aroma of knowledge… in pursuit of the truth through the bounds of humanity fulfills our experiment of life. Finding a passion in your major or your hobby is such a unique experience, and the process of paving the way for yourself is such a fun gamble. C’est la vie, damn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being knowledgeable and accumulating a taste brings you respect from other people. Moreover, it is ultimately booksmart that makes money. Do you think being cunning can make you billions? It helps, of course, but you have to at least get into college before you start a company in Silicon Valley. And the best but worst part is, most of being booksmart is fair and accessible, all you got to do is study. Yes, I know that some people don’t have access to books or a proper education, but this does not apply to the common understanding of being “knowledgeable”. In general, being booksmart is a lifestyle. It’s the attitude of being inquisitive, striving for better, constantly improving your skills, and being aware of the area for improvement. And I think this would bring happiness and success to your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not streetsmart, get that 20% of booksmarts to become “clever”. If you are streetsmart, get that 50% of booksmarts to harness your “intelligence”. Bottom line is, books do not discriminate. Being booksmart is so underrated nowadays, we have to start celebrating smart sexy people instead of bimbos. Or this is just me rambling at midnight, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Growing up, I have always considered myself a streetsmart person over a booksmart person. I was so egotistic, that I even looked down upon people that I deemed as “nerds”, aka boring people who get good grades and have virtually no personality. Booksmart is about grades (in the books), while streetsmart is about the way of life (on the streets). I did not think about the consequences of getting Cs, the most important thing in life is to crack people up with my “quick-wittedness”, y’know how teenagers roll. Peer validation was the only form of validation that matters. And so, streetsmart became the sort of branding I gave myself: I may not get the highest grades in class, but I will vouch for the happiness people’s laughter/ approval could bring me. That was my goal, I was better than the nerds because I am wittier and better at socializing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dear 19 Year Old Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/04/dear-19-year-old-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear 19 Year Old Me" /><published>2022-11-04T00:23:45-07:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T00:23:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/04/dear-19-year-old-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/11/04/dear-19-year-old-me.html">&lt;p&gt;So, here we are. You have a physics quiz next week, and I feel incredibly numb with everything in midst of transfer applications. It is almost poetic how similar your 2020 was to 2022. However, things have changed quite a bit. You have changed quite a bit. I can’t help but recollect when you felt almost sorry for yourself this year. Unfortunately, you can’t stop the development of your frontal lobe, it is going to grow no matter how hard you try. You also can’t change others’ perceptions of you, and the only person you got to impress is… yourself. And maybe your mom.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief recap: you are in America. Your fall 2021 semester was literally just you, your MacBook, and your dream. You were basically on the brink of depression, but you did not know at the time. You literally told the counselor about how you literally had 0 irl friends back then. So, thank God for physics class. You made great friends with the girls you met Day 1, and you were on track of getting your 12th chauffeur. Spring semester was pretty good, but Summer was a fever dream. You formed a cult you could never imagine forming, memories were made and shit did go down. Your first co-ed friend group since primary school. Look at you go! Celebrate little wins.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I regret to report that you did not complete the goal you set for yourself a year ago. You told yourself to “come to terms with your self-perception”; this is too big of a goal for you to complete in hindsight, and perhaps it would take you a decade more to complete this task. I don’t blame myself for failing to complete the task, I don’t think we are anywhere near understanding your self-perception. You did try to level with yourself with “becoming better leveling”, and you were trying to decipher the few characters you have of yourself with horoscopes. An effort was made.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re lucky to be in a place in life where you could constantly reinvent yourself and your image. You no longer need to dwell in the past embarrassment of the cringe, where all that is buried deep beneath the archives of Instagram. This is a great power to wield, but it also came with the tremendous responsibility of being in control of your own identity. If you are in control of your own narrative and your own LinkedIn, you have no other excuses when you are disappointed with who you are, and what you have become. At one point, you can’t separate yourself from the persona. You are what you show to people, and you need to take responsibility for that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this relates to your long-lasting ego problem. You’re 19 now, stop letting your ego get the best of you. Stop being jealous of successful people just because you think they are having a better time than you. Stop looking down at others just because you don’t think they are girlbossing hard enough. People have different priorities, people pick different paths. But when you get humbled up, don’t give in. Don’t “give up” because the world is unfair. Work harder because the world is unfair. You have nobody to compare yourself to, you have nobody to prove yourself to. I really don’t understand you sometimes, you have both a massive ego problem and a self-doubt problem. You are weird, but I believe in you nonetheless.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your pursuit of edginess makes you noble. Your delusions of grandeur compel you to become someone on a scale grander than what others can possibly imagine. Whenever you feel like losing, you need to remind yourself why you are there in the first place. Why you jumped into opportunities headfirst two years ago. Don’t ever, ever, forget that. Your 18-year-old self avoids opportunities and makes excuses for you because deep down, you feel sorry for yourself. Your 18-year-old self is not willing to face that girlboss shadow of herself because she thinks she could not be better than that. If you continue to do it, you are going to peak in high school. That is your biggest fear. Don’t avoid opportunities because you are scared.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me to your goal for your 19th year on Earth. As we can see, this is the very last of your teenage years. Where the hell’s your teenage dream??? Try to make this one good, please. I know. What the hell. The 10s ran by… what a ride. You are about to start the most overratedly good decade of your life, the 20s, so make sure you do your best and make 19 the year for the books. For this year, I want you to write the first draft. The first draft of everything, of your essays, of your activities, of the rest of yout life. It is the initiative that matters. I learned that from the romcom I watched last night, believe it or not. Start your first drafts of what you believe you will become in the future. Start your first drafts of changing your ego. Doesn’t matter how shit the start is, you have bore too much of the unbearable lightness of being. Just. Start. I thought you didn’t care what people thought.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you don’t give up whatever happens when you are 19, life has barely started. I honestly do not know which college you are going in next year, but I hope it is a college you truly like. Academics are everything and nothing. Up till this point, you have a 4.0. Another way to put is, you have nothing but a 4.0. Your ego is fragile as your 4.0. Your future employer doesn’t care about what school you were in, but you need to make sure you will thrive in these two years. The name or the ranking of the college does not matter, don’t let others make you think otherwise.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Another year ‘round the Earth, you will be fine. Everything is going to be fine. 18 could be better, could be worse. Make 19 a nice one for the last of your teenage years, alright?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">So, here we are. You have a physics quiz next week, and I feel incredibly numb with everything in midst of transfer applications. It is almost poetic how similar your 2020 was to 2022. However, things have changed quite a bit. You have changed quite a bit. I can’t help but recollect when you felt almost sorry for yourself this year. Unfortunately, you can’t stop the development of your frontal lobe, it is going to grow no matter how hard you try. You also can’t change others’ perceptions of you, and the only person you got to impress is… yourself. And maybe your mom.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Jester’s Murder</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/08/29/the-jesters-murder.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Jester’s Murder" /><published>2022-08-29T00:23:45-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-29T00:23:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/08/29/the-jesters-murder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/08/29/the-jesters-murder.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;This is a part of the ongoing series, “Becoming Better Levelling” (BBL for short).&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;In a series of self-help posts, I will be my own therapist and overshare. I think a very important part of BBL is to confront my problems head-to-head, like facing myself in the mirror and popping those terrible, oily, and snowy pimples out metaphorically. It is painful and you bleed a lot, but the longer you ignore it the deeper it festers. These are manifestos of how I aspire to become better in an abstract, introspective way.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    A new goal of mine is to stop being funny.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Or, to be more precise, stop doing things for the sake of being funny, i.e. doing things “as a joke”.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    According to “The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck” by Mark Manson, people typically have good and bad values to navigate their actions. Good values include honesty, kindness, and courage, while bad values can range from popularity and materialism, to the abstract idea of wealth and success. Manson defines good values as “reality-based, socially constructive, immediate and controllable”, while bad values are “superstitious, socially destructive, and not immediate or controllable”. Bad values may bring you temporary happiness, but they ultimately do not add any meaning to your sad, miserable life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Now comes the question: is “being funny” a good or bad value? Should I stop my pursuit of “being funny” to ascend to a higher level of NGAF?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    It comes down to “why” questions. Why do I like being funny? Because it gives me charisma. Why do I want charisma? Because it makes me feel confident. Why do I want confidence? Because it blocks out my self-doubt. Why- oh.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I think doing a lot of things “as a joke” is very funny. The pinnacle of comedy, if you will. But the catch to this form of comedy, is that not everyone is in for the joke. Best case scenario, everyone gets it and finds it very funny (e.g. proposing to a girl at Christmas Party in a drama performance of Love is An Open Door). Worst case scenario, nobody understands the joke and is very concerned about your behavior (e.g. calling your mom about a sewageside and bulimia joke you made).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    So. My deep-rooted pursuit of comedy all came down to self-doubt. I think behind my social mask (at least for now) lies a lot in hiding the “quirky” side of me. Let’s call that my Scorpio Sun. My Scorpio Sun was my key driving force from 2016 to approximately 2020, where all I expanded my horizons by exploring different types of media. The Beatles, Oscar Wilde, Films &lt;i&gt;(not movies, mind you)&lt;/i&gt; and Visual Kei fascinated me. I would announce my love for those subjects to everyone with pride, hoping they would react in awe or say “you have great taste, what an old soul”. Over the years, I have deemed that side of myself too edgy, pretentious and annoying, so I slowly buried that side so I am not as insufferable. I confronted that persona the same way I am confronting my funny side today. I feared that version of myself, the Scorpio Sun, was repulsive and disgusting. So, in order to hide that hipster away, I went on autopilot with my Sagittarius persona.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    And that was my fatal error. My Sagittarius Rising: goofy, annoying, witty. That is the jester in me, the that’s-what-she-said persona that is intensely fun and enthusiastic. I can’t deny that this funny bone has always been in me, the pursuit of being the “class clown” without necessarily chasing popularity (i.e. would have been a Leo rising if I needed that). I was sure that this side of me I presented to everyone was my “best”. And so it goes, the autopilot mode in beta testing turns into my defense mechanism. My nonchalantness-of-it-all sometimes gives people the wrong idea of me being shallow, perverted, and distasteful. Jokers are good at telling jokes, but jesters are good at making a fool of themselves. I am a silly-ol’ jester delusional enough to think that they are being a great joker.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    But there is no objectively “best” side. You see, my Scorpio Sun is quite repulsive indeed, but it gave me my unquestionable taste for aristocratic nostalgia. I need to un-brainwash myself from thinking that  And that is why my Pisces Moon comes in: every time I write, my Pisces Moon takes the wheel and becomes my key driving force, being in too deep with my emotions. She’s quite underrated, I would give her credit for giving me my pursuit of ambiguity and androgyny. In the process of my BBL, I will bring back the balance of the three, for none of them could survive without one another. Is it possible? Will I finally make the lovely comprise with all three of them? This might take years, but I believe in my own ability in introspection.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Back to the question. “Being funny” is not inherently bad, but I do find that the root of my pursuit of comedy is quite suffocating. It has triumphed over other sides to my good qualities, and I probably got the short side of the deal (imagine trying THIS hard just to get people laugh). Hope this makes sense to you, it does to me. The constant motif of my identity and my prism of “sides” deserves to have its own Wikipedia page. Oh and, instead of using the zodiac BS, I could call them the Hipster, the Romantic, and the Jester. Consider this my version of Frida Kahlo’s introspective paintings.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">This is a part of the ongoing series, “Becoming Better Levelling” (BBL for short). In a series of self-help posts, I will be my own therapist and overshare. I think a very important part of BBL is to confront my problems head-to-head, like facing myself in the mirror and popping those terrible, oily, and snowy pimples out metaphorically. It is painful and you bleed a lot, but the longer you ignore it the deeper it festers. These are manifestos of how I aspire to become better in an abstract, introspective way. A new goal of mine is to stop being funny. Or, to be more precise, stop doing things for the sake of being funny, i.e. doing things “as a joke”. According to “The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck” by Mark Manson, people typically have good and bad values to navigate their actions. Good values include honesty, kindness, and courage, while bad values can range from popularity and materialism, to the abstract idea of wealth and success. Manson defines good values as “reality-based, socially constructive, immediate and controllable”, while bad values are “superstitious, socially destructive, and not immediate or controllable”. Bad values may bring you temporary happiness, but they ultimately do not add any meaning to your sad, miserable life. Now comes the question: is “being funny” a good or bad value? Should I stop my pursuit of “being funny” to ascend to a higher level of NGAF? It comes down to “why” questions. Why do I like being funny? Because it gives me charisma. Why do I want charisma? Because it makes me feel confident. Why do I want confidence? Because it blocks out my self-doubt. Why- oh. I think doing a lot of things “as a joke” is very funny. The pinnacle of comedy, if you will. But the catch to this form of comedy, is that not everyone is in for the joke. Best case scenario, everyone gets it and finds it very funny (e.g. proposing to a girl at Christmas Party in a drama performance of Love is An Open Door). Worst case scenario, nobody understands the joke and is very concerned about your behavior (e.g. calling your mom about a sewageside and bulimia joke you made). So. My deep-rooted pursuit of comedy all came down to self-doubt. I think behind my social mask (at least for now) lies a lot in hiding the “quirky” side of me. Let’s call that my Scorpio Sun. My Scorpio Sun was my key driving force from 2016 to approximately 2020, where all I expanded my horizons by exploring different types of media. The Beatles, Oscar Wilde, Films (not movies, mind you) and Visual Kei fascinated me. I would announce my love for those subjects to everyone with pride, hoping they would react in awe or say “you have great taste, what an old soul”. Over the years, I have deemed that side of myself too edgy, pretentious and annoying, so I slowly buried that side so I am not as insufferable. I confronted that persona the same way I am confronting my funny side today. I feared that version of myself, the Scorpio Sun, was repulsive and disgusting. So, in order to hide that hipster away, I went on autopilot with my Sagittarius persona. And that was my fatal error. My Sagittarius Rising: goofy, annoying, witty. That is the jester in me, the that’s-what-she-said persona that is intensely fun and enthusiastic. I can’t deny that this funny bone has always been in me, the pursuit of being the “class clown” without necessarily chasing popularity (i.e. would have been a Leo rising if I needed that). I was sure that this side of me I presented to everyone was my “best”. And so it goes, the autopilot mode in beta testing turns into my defense mechanism. My nonchalantness-of-it-all sometimes gives people the wrong idea of me being shallow, perverted, and distasteful. Jokers are good at telling jokes, but jesters are good at making a fool of themselves. I am a silly-ol’ jester delusional enough to think that they are being a great joker. But there is no objectively “best” side. You see, my Scorpio Sun is quite repulsive indeed, but it gave me my unquestionable taste for aristocratic nostalgia. I need to un-brainwash myself from thinking that And that is why my Pisces Moon comes in: every time I write, my Pisces Moon takes the wheel and becomes my key driving force, being in too deep with my emotions. She’s quite underrated, I would give her credit for giving me my pursuit of ambiguity and androgyny. In the process of my BBL, I will bring back the balance of the three, for none of them could survive without one another. Is it possible? Will I finally make the lovely comprise with all three of them? This might take years, but I believe in my own ability in introspection. Back to the question. “Being funny” is not inherently bad, but I do find that the root of my pursuit of comedy is quite suffocating. It has triumphed over other sides to my good qualities, and I probably got the short side of the deal (imagine trying THIS hard just to get people laugh). Hope this makes sense to you, it does to me. The constant motif of my identity and my prism of “sides” deserves to have its own Wikipedia page. Oh and, instead of using the zodiac BS, I could call them the Hipster, the Romantic, and the Jester. Consider this my version of Frida Kahlo’s introspective paintings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Becoming Better Levelling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/08/23/becoming-better.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming Better Levelling" /><published>2022-08-23T00:23:45-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-23T00:23:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/08/23/becoming-better</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/08/23/becoming-better.html">&lt;p&gt;
    I would regard myself as being in some sort of “flop era” ever since I graduated high school. The quarantine period was one of the most productive phases of my life, but that is very far behind me now. There were numerous attempts on my end to rekindle my good habits, such as writing, reading, and doing my podcast, but I felt like I am in a creative gutter where I am no longer motivated to create more.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I never felt like I had to impress anyone. Well, maybe when I was doing college applications, but I don’t think that stemmed from any of my insecurities. My intention with starting all of these side projects was just to prove a point, a point that probably does not matter to me anymore. Does anyone care if I am multifaceted? The only person I have left to impress is myself, and as Lorde said, she is so hard to please (but she is a forest fire indeed).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I haven’t felt at ease since 2020. With meeting new people in college, identifying with my own accomplishments, and being comfortable with where I am at in general, there is always some sort of cognitive dissonance between how I feel versus how I think I &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; feel.  I know myself enough to know my potentials and capabilities, but I don’t know if just “knowing” is enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    We all have different sides of ourselves to show to different people. We camouflage and adapt to different environments, and it is a coping mechanism so we wouldn’t get hurt. Friends, family, lovers, and yourself. And I believe that there is not a single form that defines us as a person, it is always a combination of all these sides. One of the common themes in my writing is about being ambiguous and leaving much room for imagination, and I think the way I write can truly display how I think as I mature. If you know me personally, you might have yet to meet my other sides: the literary giant, the STEMinist, the misandrist, the comedian, and the immature version of me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    But sometimes, I feel an invisible, strong force that compells me to abandon all these ordained versions and craft a new personality. I guess this has something to do with the American myth, of how reinvention brings us new experiences. I can’t follow through with my habits, and I don’t like how perishable our stupid dreams and expectations are. Everything is futile.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Counterpoint: I guess the new and updated point I need to prove is that I am enough. I should stop beating myself up for how I stopped blogging, reading, or doing my podcast. Instead, I should just get started with becoming better myself. I will start writing more (very therapeutic), reading self-help books, start flossing, and sleeping earlier. I want to feel better about the person I am today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;i&gt; &lt;i&gt;
    Whatever happened to the girl I knew?
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
    In the wasteland, come up short and end up on the news?
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
    Father John Misty, Buddy’s Rendevous
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I would regard myself as being in some sort of “flop era” ever since I graduated high school. The quarantine period was one of the most productive phases of my life, but that is very far behind me now. There were numerous attempts on my end to rekindle my good habits, such as writing, reading, and doing my podcast, but I felt like I am in a creative gutter where I am no longer motivated to create more. I never felt like I had to impress anyone. Well, maybe when I was doing college applications, but I don’t think that stemmed from any of my insecurities. My intention with starting all of these side projects was just to prove a point, a point that probably does not matter to me anymore. Does anyone care if I am multifaceted? The only person I have left to impress is myself, and as Lorde said, she is so hard to please (but she is a forest fire indeed). I haven’t felt at ease since 2020. With meeting new people in college, identifying with my own accomplishments, and being comfortable with where I am at in general, there is always some sort of cognitive dissonance between how I feel versus how I think I should feel. I know myself enough to know my potentials and capabilities, but I don’t know if just “knowing” is enough. We all have different sides of ourselves to show to different people. We camouflage and adapt to different environments, and it is a coping mechanism so we wouldn’t get hurt. Friends, family, lovers, and yourself. And I believe that there is not a single form that defines us as a person, it is always a combination of all these sides. One of the common themes in my writing is about being ambiguous and leaving much room for imagination, and I think the way I write can truly display how I think as I mature. If you know me personally, you might have yet to meet my other sides: the literary giant, the STEMinist, the misandrist, the comedian, and the immature version of me. But sometimes, I feel an invisible, strong force that compells me to abandon all these ordained versions and craft a new personality. I guess this has something to do with the American myth, of how reinvention brings us new experiences. I can’t follow through with my habits, and I don’t like how perishable our stupid dreams and expectations are. Everything is futile. Counterpoint: I guess the new and updated point I need to prove is that I am enough. I should stop beating myself up for how I stopped blogging, reading, or doing my podcast. Instead, I should just get started with becoming better myself. I will start writing more (very therapeutic), reading self-help books, start flossing, and sleeping earlier. I want to feel better about the person I am today. Whatever happened to the girl I knew? In the wasteland, come up short and end up on the news? Father John Misty, Buddy’s Rendevous</summary></entry></feed>