<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-17T16:48:38-07:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">In Her Own Write</title><subtitle>Eternal malaise of the soul.</subtitle><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><entry><title type="html">All Love Is Never Lost</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/poetry/2025/03/15/all-love-is-never-lost.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All Love Is Never Lost" /><published>2025-03-15T12:45:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T12:45:00-07:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/poetry/2025/03/15/all-love-is-never-lost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/poetry/2025/03/15/all-love-is-never-lost.html">&lt;p&gt;All love is never lost.&lt;br /&gt;
Some love is frozen—&lt;br /&gt;
locked in winter’s grasp,&lt;br /&gt;
molecules clutching each other &lt;br /&gt;
like hands unwilling to let go.&lt;br /&gt;
It waits in the frost, untouched,&lt;br /&gt;
preserved but distant,&lt;br /&gt;
a memory encased in ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some love melts—&lt;br /&gt;
it runs, reshapes, bends,&lt;br /&gt;
a river without a destination.&lt;br /&gt;
It kisses the earth, fills empty spaces,&lt;br /&gt;
becomes something new with every twist and turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some love burns—&lt;br /&gt;
it flares too bright, too fierce,&lt;br /&gt;
petrifying those who do not dare to hold the scathing flame.&lt;br /&gt;
It cracks open, shatters,&lt;br /&gt;
then vanishes into the air, unseen.&lt;br /&gt;
But even then, it lingers—&lt;br /&gt;
a whisper in the wind, a shimmer in the heat,&lt;br /&gt;
weightless but waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But love never disappears.&lt;br /&gt;
It rises, condenses, falls again,&lt;br /&gt;
a cycle written in the sky,&lt;br /&gt;
etching itself into the delicate fog on your window,&lt;br /&gt;
waiting to be seen—&lt;br /&gt;
Even in atomic moments, &lt;br /&gt;
what once seems lost returns, softened, purified,&lt;br /&gt;
is always ready to flow back into your heart,&lt;br /&gt;
never far from eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when we leave this Earth, &lt;br /&gt;
our love transforms to plasma.&lt;br /&gt;
Shifting into aurora australis,&lt;br /&gt;
or the distant stars lightyears away,&lt;br /&gt;
immortalized.&lt;br /&gt;
Boundless, free of sorrow,&lt;br /&gt;
it dances on the edge of eternity.&lt;br /&gt;
And those that remain&lt;br /&gt;
will feel your love’s tender caress, &lt;br /&gt;
like moonlight on their skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love is never lost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If not reciprocated, it will flow back and soften and purify the heart.
&lt;em&gt;-Washington Irving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“and in the end
the love you take
is equal to the love
you make”
&lt;em&gt;-The Beatles, The End&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">All love is never lost. Some love is frozen— locked in winter’s grasp, molecules clutching each other like hands unwilling to let go. It waits in the frost, untouched, preserved but distant, a memory encased in ice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dissecting male attention in business terms</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/03/14/microdosing-male-attn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dissecting male attention in business terms" /><published>2025-03-14T00:14:45-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-14T00:14:45-07:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/03/14/microdosing-male-attn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/03/14/microdosing-male-attn.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/b&gt; The truth of the matter is, I didn’t want to be this cynical and Machiavellian about love. Relationships are not supposed to be zero-sum games. But when the game is rigged against people like us, and when men take advantage of the trust and care we give them, this approach allows you to enjoy male attention while keeping yourself safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disclaimer No. 2:&lt;/b&gt; The second truth is, as my friend Angie says, I hate men who are mfs. And most men are mfs. None of us need male attention to survive... but, boy, is it fun. It’s like weed. You use it to feel alive, to get that high, but don’t become so addicted that you start thinking, &quot;I need him.&quot; Use it sparingly; don’t let the drug use you. You control it—always remember that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered the disclaimers, here’s how to safely microdose male attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;1. Don’t Love the Players, Love the Game&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on your strategy and personal goals, not on any one person. Ask yourself: What do I want from this? A relationship? Instant gratification? Or just attention I didn&apos;t get as a kid? In business, the goal is to stay objective and focus on the long-term strategy—not getting emotionally entangled in the success or failure of any one deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing that can happen is losing yourself in someone. When you love the player (not the game), the ship starts sinking, and you lose yourself. But when you focus on the game, you know when to leave, when to “jump ship”—and that gives you clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loving the game means each player serves a purpose, and you can walk away when they no longer serve you. It’s about maintaining control and realizing that control doesn’t mean manipulation—it means having the option to walk away whenever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if a deal goes sour, reflect on what you could have done differently. That makes the experience about learning, not about loss. Like I said, love should never be a zero-sum game—attachment makes it one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;2. Diversification in Investments: Always Have a Roster&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a roster is the best way to prevent attachment. I made the mistake of letting my roster go once I found someone I thought was worth investing in—but I was wrong. It’s like sales: nothing is finalized until the deal is closed. Until you cuff or get cuffed, you have the right to have a roster. Having multiple options prevents you from pouring all your emotional energy into one person (your &quot;stock&quot;) and getting too attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re focused on just one player, all your emotional eggs are in that basket. Sometimes, you’re reluctant to cut your losses because you feel like walking away will cost you everything. This makes relationships a zero-sum game because you’ve invested more than you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of having a roster is not to manipulate your players or toy with their feelings. It is simply to retain sobriety and remind yourself that you are in control. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;3. Microdose Your Attention&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the sales strategy comes in: drip-feeding value to keep the other party interested, without giving everything upfront. Think of it as supply and demand. When you offer something valuable but in small doses, it creates a sense of demand—keeping them coming back for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you over-deliver too soon, they take you for granted. But when you limit access, they begin to see you as high-value and realize you won’t tolerate disrespect or stick around for scraps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to the roster—since you aren’t giving anyone everything at once, they won’t get tired of you. They won’t have the opportunity to take you for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t put all your eggs in one basket. It&apos;s a simple investment strategy: diversify your “portfolio.” When one stock disappoints, you move on without losing everything. Unless you’re 120% sure about a particular stock’s value or loyalty, never go all in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Will This Fulfill You?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it depends. If you’re looking for high returns, maybe not. But if you want low risks, this approach should work well. It leaves room for the possibility of reward—romantic or otherwise. It&apos;s basic investment economics: high-risk, high-return; low-risk, low-return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re seeking deep emotional connections and long-term investing, this “microdosing” approach may feel unsatisfying or superficial. But here’s my take: After experiencing deep emotional connections and still being severely let down, I don’t think it’s worth it. Men (mfs) have mastered enjoying attention without expecting commitment. We should do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shouldn’t seek star-crossed love from men with the emotional depth of a kiddie pool. Instead, seek multitudes within yourself. This strategy helps maintain balance and manage the expectation that not every connection needs to be deep and life-changing. I don’t need another man roaming this Earth with the knowledge of my deepest, darkest secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of whether this microdosing strategy will fulfill you ultimately comes down to personal preference. Understanding this business-savvy approach to male attention reflects boundaries, emotional self-preservation, and risk management. After all, men are not FDIC insured.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="opinion" /><summary type="html">Disclaimer: The truth of the matter is, I didn’t want to be this cynical and Machiavellian about love. Relationships are not supposed to be zero-sum games. But when the game is rigged against people like us, and when men take advantage of the trust and care we give them, this approach allows you to enjoy male attention while keeping yourself safe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Telling Your Teddy</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/monologue/2025/03/08/telling-your-teddy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Telling Your Teddy" /><published>2025-03-08T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2025-03-08T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/monologue/2025/03/08/telling-your-teddy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/monologue/2025/03/08/telling-your-teddy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(Spotlight on. You sit on the edge of your bed, a solemn expression on your face. In your hands, a small stuffed bear with slightly matted fur, a relic of something from the past. You take a deep breath and begin, voice soft but serious.)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, buddy. Hey, little guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got a second?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen, um… I don’t really know how to say this, but… your father’s gone. He—he left us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Pause. Deep breath.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, I know. I thought he’d stay too. I thought he loved us. I mean, he used to hold you at night. Used to squeeze you when he couldn’t quite squeeze me. Remember when he won you at that stupid claw machine and said, “Look, now you’ll always have a piece of me”? Yeah, well, none of that was true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Stands up from edge of bed, walks towards center of stage. Bear still in hand. Spotlight follows.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should’ve seen the signs. We were always somewhere in between. I pick and choose the signs to see. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, here we are. Just you and me, kid. Just like your grandmother always said: “Men will leave, but stuffed animals are forever.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;(You hold the bear up, looking into its beady plastic eyes. Voice thick with mock emotion.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to tell you about this information, I mean, what kind of parent would I be to burden the kid with things like this? It is not your fault. I won’t punish you for what he did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t you worry. I’m not going anywhere. I’ll take care of you. I’ll provide. I’ll make sure you have a nice spot on my bed. We’ll make something up for the other stuffed animals at school. My love won’t be flaky. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Beat. You pat its little head.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not his story, this is ours. We don’t need him. We’ll be okay. And if not… well, at least you’re machine washable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Blackout.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="monologue" /><summary type="html">(Spotlight on. You sit on the edge of your bed, a solemn expression on your face. In your hands, a small stuffed bear with slightly matted fur, a relic of something from the past. You take a deep breath and begin, voice soft but serious.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">art manifesto (wilde style)</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/personal/2025/02/18/art.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="art manifesto (wilde style)" /><published>2025-02-18T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/personal/2025/02/18/art</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/personal/2025/02/18/art.html">&lt;p&gt;my urge to write is almost primal. if i cant create, i will cease to exist. if i dont make art, me and my stillbirth creativity will die from the emotional blood loss. its maternal. its divine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;inside of me are millions of words, each with its own universes, eagerly waiting for their emancipations. art is within you, and the mother before you, and the mother before her. art is conceived through divine intervention and not carnal sins. most ideas die. some survive. few make it to full term. i am the madonna of my art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to create art is to suffer. art is suffering. the epidural is to romanticize. happiness is one-dimensional; sadness is a galvanizing prism of misery. and art is bred through melancholy. before you even notice, you are with art. and to abort your art is to deny the immaculate conception. it is creative castration. you deny yourself from the divine pleasures of seeing your art flourish, to breathe life into something beyond yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to create art is to salvage. art is salvation. men could never understand the blissful catharsis to create to something so beautiful after so much struggle and torture. to look at art as life, and life art. oh, to hold your babe in your arms for the first time. to press its soft head gently against your bare chest, and hush it for the first time ever. that must be beautiful. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">my urge to write is almost primal. if i cant create, i will cease to exist. if i dont make art, me and my stillbirth creativity will die from the emotional blood loss. its maternal. its divine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">涅瓦河的隱秘</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/fiction/2025/02/16/neva.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="涅瓦河的隱秘" /><published>2025-02-16T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/fiction/2025/02/16/neva</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/fiction/2025/02/16/neva.html">&lt;p&gt;「那裡，在寥廓的海波之旁 &lt;br&gt;
他站著，充滿了偉大的思想，&lt;br&gt;
向遠方凝視。在他前面&lt;br&gt;
河水廣闊地奔流……」&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;這是雅立在涅瓦河邊，彼得大帝青銅像的描述。涅瓦河，見證了聖彼特堡的榮辱與興衰。那河畔的建築經歷了革命的風雨，目睹了一個國家的成長。在雄偉的涅瓦河邊, 在濔漫著寒冷乾燥的氣味的冬天，看著大江東去，沙皇的風光一時，令人不禁嘆息。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;涅瓦河位於聖彼特堡的中心，站在岸邊，可以重現逝去的沙俄大帝國王朝的輝煌：兩旁的教堂，是王朝為下的歷史古蹟。其中的濺血教堂，擁有東正教堂的穹頂，雖說別具色彩，但色澤冷黯無神，暗帶悲傷。俄羅斯中世紀的建築風格，日漸失修的朱紅血色外牆，彷彿經歷了無盡委屈。所謂的「濺血」，是早在革命之前，19世紀沙皇亞歷山大二世在教堂旁被刺殺，而命名為血濺教堂的哀悼。如今，宗教在人民的生活當中不再重要，聖彼特堡的教堂原有的威嚴已經早在俄國革命中被洗劫一空。這是俄國歷史上第一場的罪與罰，是往後俄國革命的預兆，就發生在涅瓦河的岸邊。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;涅瓦河的另一邊，彼得保羅教堂的對面，還有一個雄踞在旁的歷史古蹟—冬宮。金碧輝煌的裝飾配上高貴淡綠的外牆，從涅瓦河邊望過去，已經感受到沙俄皇朝的威嚴，令人肅然起敬。這是歷代沙皇自18世紀以來定居的皇宮，奢華設計目不暇給。現在變成了博物館的冬宮，任人進入參觀：幻想童話般的皇家在此宮殿裡生活，兩個世紀前多麼的富麗堂皇！然而，這個雕欄玉砌的建築背後，蘊藏著俄國有血有淚的辛酸史—十月革命的洗禮。血腥星期日於冬宮廣場發生，在民眾與軍隊的衝突之中，一千多人在此喪生。1917年，工人軍人為推翻臨時政府，突襲冬宮，把一個沉睡中的民族喚醒，冬宮不復從前的純真，變成了人們對貴族皇朝所仇恨的象徵。正當國家動盪，民憤四處的同時，涅瓦河面結成冰，殘冬只遺下了一份血腥腥的滄桑。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;冬天過後，涅瓦河帶著逐漸融去的冰塊流淌。新的春風景氣吹遍聖彼特堡。在這個經歷了三次革命的城市，大地萬象更新，新的政府為人民帶來新的希望，忘卻舊代王朝的腐敗衰落。革命就是如此簡單嗎？把舊社會打個流花落水，換來的只剩頹垣敗；推翻一個王朝容易，但建立一個政府困難。歷史重是驚人的相似，涅瓦河照舊奔流，警告俄羅斯不要重蹈覆轍。這段令人唏噓的歷史，恐怕只剩下涅瓦河得以保存三百年前的樣貌了。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="fiction" /><category term="chinese" /><summary type="html">「那裡，在寥廓的海波之旁 他站著，充滿了偉大的思想， 向遠方凝視。在他前面 河水廣闊地奔流……」</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Thrilling, Confusing, Short-Lived, Torrid Love Affair</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/anecdote/2025/02/14/My-Thrilling-Confusing-Short-Lived-Torrid-Love-Affair.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Thrilling, Confusing, Short-Lived, Torrid Love Affair" /><published>2025-02-14T23:15:35-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T23:15:35-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/anecdote/2025/02/14/My-Thrilling-Confusing-Short-Lived-Torrid-Love-Affair</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/anecdote/2025/02/14/My-Thrilling-Confusing-Short-Lived-Torrid-Love-Affair.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Valentine’s Day. In the past 96 hours, I have experienced one of the most thrilling, insane, upsetting yet rewarding week I have ever had. I had quite a love affair with venture capitalism. Or perhaps “a brief flirtation” would describe what happened more accurately, but it is my crashout so I get to call it whatever I want. I also feel like writing a four-thousand-word blogpost for “a brief flirtation” would make me sound insane. And for those that are updated with the recent ronilore and very disappointed, yes, it was clickbait; but please hear me out, as the lore does go hard on this one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not know, I am quite the CS major. I am a very engineering-minded, problem-solving-oriented person, but I am also a yapper. Sometimes I find myself pondering if this is the right career path for me, as the stereotypical engineer are usually socially inept losers that only communicates through discord. But that does not apply to me, and I don’t know if that is truly “my calling”. I enjoy what I do, and over the years I have adapted into the space a little more than what I’d like to believe, but I am still not fully convinced that I should be doing SWE my entire life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, naturally, I decided to try out some of the entrepreneurship classes offered at Berkeley. To be honest, I am initially not even that interested in founding startups and stuff. I am not a risk taker. I believed that it is hard for rookies like me to break into investing/ entrepreneurship because a) I don’t have the financial literacy to do it, b) I don’t believe in investing as my main source of income, and c) I have seen too many cases where investments (stocks, real estate, just anything tbh) turn south, and I don’t think I want to gamble with my hard-earned money like that. But, since I am at Silicon Valley, where technology entrepreneurship is actually THE way to make an impact and make a name of yourself (a bit of an American Dream there eh), I decided to dip my toes in and try it out a little. Berkeley’s entrepreneurship program is like, their flagship stuff. Not every school has the resources for these classes. I personally cannot conceive that many unique ideas, but if somebody else comes up with something cool, I don’t mind joining a team and help out with my skills as an engineer. So that is my mindset coming into the whole entrepreneurial thing. You can say my reason is somewhat superficial: I am not here just to make money, I am here to make a lasting impact that can make people’s lives easier, even if at a miniscule level. It was quite innocent of a mindset to get into the whole entrepreneurship thingy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And boy, did I try my best. I got into the SCET program at Berkeley, where they basically incubate undergrads to come up with their own startups, and potentially receive funding to turn their ideas into venture-backed companies. I really wanted the SCET certificate because I thought it would help me with applying to grad school some day, if I ever decide to go. And so, for my last semester as an undergrad, I am taking 3 entrepreneur classes: a class about how to start a startup with sustainability and ethics in mind, a class all about the business and steps in creating a tech startup, and a class about leveraging data as a way to stand out from the crowd and have a good business model. And I was going to only take 2 out of the 3 classes (for the certificate), but I loved all three classes so much that I decided to keep all 3. Was it an overkill? Most definitely. But this is lowkey the first time during my 2 years at Berkeley where I feel like I am truly taking classes for the sake of learning, not to fulfill the graduation requirement or fill up my units. Like, oh my god. I am actually interested in learning all of this. I don’t get to learn this from anywhere else, but the #1 school with undergrad founders. So yes, it was wonderful, and I was so ready to commit to this program, even if I am not going to be an actual entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that was my plan up till last week. I have been consistently participating in classes, I crack a couple of jokes during class here and there, I get called out by my professors for being on the laptop or whatever, but it’s been going alright. Then, last week, as I was lining up to kiss the professor’s ass after lecture, one of the TAs called me over and said she has something to discuss with me. She is the TA for two out of the three classes I am in, so I suppose that I have made an impression. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, Veronica, right?” &lt;br&gt;

“Yes, am I in trouble or something?” I try to recall if I used AI for the last assignment.&lt;br&gt;

“Do you have any experience with venture capitalism?”&lt;br&gt;

“Um, I have worked at a startup before, so I guess?”&lt;br&gt;

“Well… okay it doesn’t matter. There is this venture capitalism competition that is happening next Saturday, and a team still needs two people. So, I want to see if you are interested in joining the team.”&lt;br&gt;

“Um… sure.”&lt;br&gt;

“There is a workshop happening right now, so we will need to go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she was packing, I texted my friends that I had dinner/ alcohol plans with. I told them some crazy opportunity just came up so I couldn’t make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rushed to the workshop, and by the time I got there, it was time for the mock presentation for the teams to present to the (actual) venture capitalists to show them what they’ve learn in the past three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you, I just got there, and I lowkey don’t know a single VC term. I didn’t know TAM, SAM, SOM, or LTV:CAC ratio, just any of the crazy terms. I was an eager noob. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met the two guys that are left in the team. There were 5 people originally, 3 dropped out due to various unreasonable reasons, a girl from a different team joined, and now they need two more people. Let’s just call those two, Andy and Caleb. They were super nice, super accommodating, and reassured me that they won’t be mad even if I don’t know what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it in very vulgar terms, I rawdogged the mock presentation. I went in there with my super cute outfit and boot heels, I told the venture capitalists that I have an engineering background, and I brought in all the excitement that I had with this crazy fun opportunity, and I acted as professional and business-y as I could. I used some technical engineering terms, I questioned the founder’s idea behind the AI use, and I raised questions about their business model. The VCs did not grill me too hard, although the guy said I had “too much energy”. But the VC lady loved it, and I think I did well. It was such an incredible experience, and I was almost starstrucked with talking to actual, professional VCs working in Silicon Valley. I mean, these are the actual sharks of shark tank. They were a little mean sometimes, but, they earned the right to be mean. And they are business people that sign million-dollar deals, making million dollar decisions. Of course they are a little mean, why wouldn’t they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a bit of a Cinderella moment for me. Before this opportunity, I accepted my fate as a CS major that is destined to be the builder/ engineer, but never the presenter. I have always knew that my strongest skillset lies in the way I make connections and network with people, as well as improvisational comedy and just being a crazy public speaker (due to the lack of social cues). I am aware of my talents/ skillsets, but I also wanted the safest way to make money/ an impact, plus I am pretty good at math. So I thought I could just put my dreams of being a professional social person on the backlog for now. But with this world of venture capitalism, it combines my greatest two interests in life: the theatrics of persuasion and public speaking, and also the technicality in engineering and innovation. Venture capitalism is truly the best of two worlds. I use my engineering domain knowledge to make business decisions. Plus, it’s technically not my money. It’s the LPs. So, I thought this might be my true, true calling. And it is not too late discovering your true, true calling three weeks into the last semester of your undergrad, right? I still have the rest of my life to figure it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing. I enjoyed chilling with the two teammates, and I had a nice time briefing texting the other girl. Let’s call her Blaire. Andy offered to teach me a little more of the VC jargon/ terms that’s foreign to me, an offer which I gladly accepted. Caleb is a sophomore that is super sweet and has this almost childlike charm that reminded me of a younger version of myself, before I got jaded and disillusioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some personal stuff happened over the weekend, but I was still so excited for the competition. I even had Valentine’s Day blocked out for this competition, so I know I won’t be alone. Fast forward to Tuesday, I texted the groupchat if anyone wants to hang out and teach me a little bit more for the competition. Andy DMed me, and said he is down to come over and help me. We live in the same building, so it is not that hard to hang out. I thought we were going to the study lounge, but he straight asked me my room number. Naturally, I gave him my room number. He’s like “I’ll hurry over” and came at around 10pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was quite adamant about taking his shoes off, I am not sure why. I gave him some spare slippers, he tried and told me they were too small for him. We both laughed. He threw his dirty ass backpack onto my bed, and sat on it when his street clothes. I was pretty startled, as my bedsheets were very clean and shouldn’t be touched with outside stuff. You know what I mean. But he just treated the place like it’s his. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down and went over the VC razor checklist. He went over the details, and I asked questions. He is an econ major, and when we talked about the market and stuff, I gave him the chance to mansplain macroeconomics to me. He gladly took the offer and started yapping about government bonds and stuff. Despite the fact that it is all basic information any econ major would know, I was quite impressed. I was also impressed by the fact that he is willing to sit down and explain all that to me. But after around 45 minutes of serious learning, I had the overwhelming urge to overshare. And I asked for his consent to overshare, he said yes. I went on a two hour rant on things that had happened in the past couple of days, and he was deeply interested in listening. And afterwards, he went on a rant about his roommate. It was really fun as I had a lot of pent-up anger and needed that to be released. We yapped until midnight, which was when we got a noise complaint. But that did not stop us, we just went to a study room to continue talking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He briefly explained some cool VC terms after switching rooms. I learned about the “pro-rata right”, which was a VC jargon that guarantees the same amount of shares the VC would have when more investors come in. It is for anti-dilution prevention, and it prevents the scene in the social network where Eduardo Saverin’s shares in Facebook was diluted after millions of new shares were distributed. It was really cool. It was interesting though, he said “pro-rata” like “pro-ray-da”, so I assumed it’s spelled as “pro-vader” or “pro-razor”. But when I googled it, it’s pronounced as “pro-rah-tah”, so I got confused. Either way, I’m glad I learned all that from him, I probably wouldn’t have the opportunity to learn any of this anyways. And side note, while I was doing my research writing this, and I discovered that Eduardo Saverin is now a venture capitalist and is the richest man in Singapore with his 2% share of Facebook. He started out as the co-founder of Facebook and is now helping out other startups. It’s all quite poetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the serious parts of our conversations, I talked about my fear for investing and how I prefer “working earnestly” as my means of production. I was obviously implying that investing is not a way to make money “earnestly”, because it is like gambling and I don’t think I am capable of making good decisions with my limited knowledge. But he raised a really good point that stayed in my mind ever since: “you cannot create generational wealth just by working hard for someone else.” And that makes a lot of sense to me all of a sudden. Generational wealth, or generational impact just by following the lead of somebody. This is why Berkeley is so keen on undergrads doing startups anyways. They want organic, home-grown innovation. And that’s so cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I do want to defend venture capitalism as like, quite an interesting and niche sector within investment and finance. It is high-risk, high-return, and they are investing in companies and make people’s dreams come true. With the stock markets and typical investing, you are not contributing to make a lasting impact on somebody/ something. But with VC, you are here to disrupt and make an impact. You get to make million-dollar decisions and take chances with helping somebody out. Obviously, VCs want high yield returns, but that comes with any business deals. I am a little swept off my feet with all these new and exciting concepts, only at places like Silicon Valley, y’know? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond venture capitalism, we talked so much about the dating scene and hookup culture. I really enjoyed the conversation as I don’t really get a candid, platonic male perspective, and he doesn’t get that with women either. It was such a 2-3AM conversation. Oh and, we also talked about classical music. I forgot how the conversation started, but we were just saying how we don’t have friends to go to recitals with, and we made the crazy decision to buy tickets to this concert the next week together. It was nice, I was genuinely making a friend. We ended up talking till 4AM. We yapped till our eyes cannot open, it was crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days leading up to the competition, I was actively recruiting for members. I invited a guy that was great at public speaking at one of the the SCET classes, who accepted them later left the team due to a scheduling conflict. I also told my professor, who is a full-time venture capitalist, about the opportunities. He was super supportive about it and gave me some tips with how it went. I also bought a suit off Amazon. I am an ENGINEER, there is like zero occasions where I need to wear a suit. Even at networking events, dressing in business casual would be deemed as overdressing. Techbros just show up in hackathon hoodies and call it a day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days before the competition, the TA found a new member. Let’s call him Dhinesh. We were running out of time, so Dhinesh was our last bet. Dhinesh and Blaire had beef and she didn’t get fully into it. And when I dmed Andy and asked why, he said Dhinesh is “fruity and weird”. I want to take his word for the weird part, but I can’t help but feel like it is very mean of me to judge somebody’s character based on whether they are fruity or not. That’s just thinly veiled homophobia, and that does not fly with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caleb and I were the only ones texting in the groupchat. Mind you, Andy and Blaire are the two more capable, and more well-versed in the VC jargon, but they were virtually silent days leading up to the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all just so sketchy. Andy, Blaire, Dhinesh and I are all seniors, while Caleb is a sophomore. I can imagine Caleb being confused with why these senior citizens are fighting like highschoolers. It was such a messy mess and I feel bad for Caleb the most. He just a baby. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there is no other way, I added Dhinesh to the groupchat. He is quite capable and enthusiastic about it. Andy and Blaire are still mute, and the three of us plan to meet the day before the competition. But 5 people were the minimum requirement, so we could just wing it. I was there to participate, to meet the VC judges and to learn more about this exciting, niche industry. What’s the worse that could happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dhinesh and I met on Google meet, the night before the competition. Caleb added everybody on a google meet link, but only the two of us showed up. We had a good time introducing ourselves, while I sorta understand what they meant by “weird”, but I still have an open heart and mind to collaborating with him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 30 minutes into the meeting, Andy hopped in out of nowhere. He told us that he and Blaire decided to withdraw, so we will not be participating. I was shocked, but I tried to keep my cool. I tend to process my feelings a lot later after my fight/ flight mode gets triggered. But Dhinesh was visibly shocked and confused. He cleared his schedule to dive into this competition head first, and I did too. 24 hours before it starts, someone decides to withdraw: the people that got screwed over decides to screw somebody else over the same way they got screwed over. He stayed to banter a little though, and we kept it very civil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours after that weird call, Dhinesh calls me to discuss what happens next. The both of us are confused. I sort of defended Andy and Blaire’s decision, as I am still trying to see the good in people and always give others the benefit of the doubt (until they cross the line). But Dhinesh and Blaire had beef tracing all the way back to freshman year, so he was not having it. And hearing how Dhinesh is not having it makes me realize that maybe I should not just sit here and agree with what others want, disregarding what I want in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, Dhinesh and I decided to hit Caleb up and ask him how he feels. Caleb wanted to do the competition so bad, and technically it is three against two, so we want to move forward with it. I also called Blaire on the phone, but she didn’t pick up. Mind you, I haven’t met her a single time up to this point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the emergency meeting, each of us explained our thoughts on how to move forward. Andy said this is not what he signed up for with the competition, he doesn’t want to be the teacher for this last-minute team. Blaire said we don’t know the terms enough and we don’t know each other well enough to be in a team together. Caleb wants to take a stab at it and he doesn’t mind the outcome regardless. Dhinesh wants to do it and expressed his frustration with just joining and team and also getting told to withdraw last minute. Last but not least, if I were a character I would probably call myself Eliza or something, but I said I just want to learn and this seemed so fun. So we voted, and 3 out of 5 people want to continue. So we worked on preparing for the competition a little, only for 30 minutes. But you can tell that Andy and Blaire were not having it. I try not to think too hard during the meeting, because I really try to see the best in people and I don’t think Andy and Blaire thinks we are beneath them necessarily. But the truth is, other teams had 3 weeks to prepare and we didn’t. And that is not anybody’s fault except for the ones that left the two guys. And Andy was the one that wrote the email saying we are withdrawing, but he didn’t want to look bad with the un-withdrawal. I could somewhat empathize but disagree with their mindsets, but it is just not fair for them to take away our chances of doing the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Caleb, Dhinesh and I talk in the groupchat about the preparation meeting. I was pulling all the strings together and messaging everybody with our plans. At around 4pm, Andy and Blaire texts the groupchat saying they have, once again, decide to withdraw. They dropped two random people in the groupchat and said, “here are two people that we found that could do the competition with y’all. Good luck.” Dhinesh and I were stressed out of our minds. Let’s call these two people, Fredrik and Gauri. I dmed the two of them, greeting them and asking them if they can meet at the library at 5pm. Fredrik responded enthusiastically. Gauri was very confused with what was happening, and asked me to explain everything. I did, and she told me that she doesn’t want to join a competition 12 hours before it begins hastily. She said she would’ve loved to join from the beginning, but given how messy it is, she doesn’t think it would be a good idea. I completely understand and small talked a little, she seems like an amazing person. Fredrik said he is available to meet with Dhinesh and I on campus at 5pm. We are still one person short, but I suppose that I could still do it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to my TA about the entire situation. She informed me that our team could NOT move forward with Fredrik in the team. He competed in the competition last year and caused a lot of drama. So, in the end, the two members that “joined the groupchat” could not actually join the group, and we could not move forward with the competition. The organizers (TA included) emailed Andy and Blaire, and they were also informed that they are unable to move the team forward without the two of them in the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met up with Dhinesh after class and called Caleb. We were actively traumabonding. We drafted up a sincerely apology of all the inconvenience caused (despite the drama not caused by us), and we wished them a nice, smooth competition the next day. All of that was sincere and true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Dhinesh and I were not satisfied with the outcome. We cleared our schedules, stayed up till 2am to study for the competition, and we don’t want other people to sabotage our learning opportunity. So we decided to finish up our VC learnings and draft up a term sheet for the competition, even if we are not competing anymore. We went to get frozen yogurt after deciding all that, and we sat in a student lounge completing all our due diligence with the competition materials. We learned all the business terms together and drafted up a pretty solid term sheet, if I do say so myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rarely do things just for the sake of learning, it is always for a grade, a certificate, or to look good. But this is the one instance where I am genuinely learning for the sake of learning. Perhaps it is to feel better about dropping out of the competition, or to learn everything “out-of-spite” so I don’t feel like I am beneath Andy and Blaire. But it didn’t matter, I had so much fun and I learned so much about the business terms with startups and investments. Now I can tell people I have drafted up term sheets before, and I won’t be ripped off at car dealerships anymore. Dhinesh was also incredibly motivated to learn, so, I am glad I had him to learn with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also talked a lot of shit about Blaire. Dhinesh told me that Blaire acted cold and stand-offish towards him since the beginning. And to be real with you, I think I understand what Andy meant we they said Dhinesh is “kinda off”; he goes on his phone when I’m talking to him and farted multiple times. The amount of dirt he said about Blaire was also just, a little much. I was matching his energy, but I do feel a bit bad talking shit about a girl that I haven’t even met. But this isn’t high school. This isn’t “popular kids don’t play with weird losers”. It is rather juvenile to refuse to collaborate with someone smart simply because you find their vibe to be “kinda off”, or had drama with almost three years ago. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so tired by the end of the night, my accent was slipping. I was on power-saving mode. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I texted Andy the next day (which is today), telling him not to feel too bad about it. He is still a super knowledgeable finance bro/ budding venture capitalist, so I want to introduce my CEO on a separate startup project (for the entrepreneurship classes) to him and ask for some advice. He thanked me and we are still cool; we are still going to the recital next Friday together after all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I walked away without burning a single bridge, something I try my best to do in every situation. But I probably won’t be close friends with any of these people anyway. This is probably not my crowd. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave this crazy, thrilling world of venture capitalism and business like Nick Carraway leaving New York. My mind was absolutely blown, but my heart was incredibly let down. It debunked some of my assumptions— that business/ finance is not just about being ruthless and insane, it could also be a platform that leverages money to make people’s dreams come true; but it has also confirmed my hypothesis— that the business world is, at its core, dark, cutthroat, and evil. It’s full of fake people backstabbing each other. And at the end of the day, it’s every man for himself. I get it, but I also cannot believe how it played out. But if I can’t make a LinkedIn post out of this experience, the least I can do is write a blogpost about it. And that is exactly what I am doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, software engineering is most definitely still my calling, for now. But I am open to new opportunities and would love to rekindle this affair with venture capitalism some time. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="anecdote" /><summary type="html">Happy Valentine’s Day. In the past 96 hours, I have experienced one of the most thrilling, insane, upsetting yet rewarding week I have ever had. I had quite a love affair with venture capitalism. Or perhaps “a brief flirtation” would describe what happened more accurately, but it is my crashout so I get to call it whatever I want. I also feel like writing a four-thousand-word blogpost for “a brief flirtation” would make me sound insane. And for those that are updated with the recent ronilore and very disappointed, yes, it was clickbait; but please hear me out, as the lore does go hard on this one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">can men and women be platonic friends</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/01/29/platonic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="can men and women be platonic friends" /><published>2025-01-29T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/01/29/platonic</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/opinion/2025/01/29/platonic.html">&lt;p&gt;guys i think i cooked with this one. lately i have this new theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yes, but under one condition: mental castration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and they are only platonic when both have mutually castrated/ neutered each other. by that i mean, when neither parties don’t acknowledge that they are sexually viable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when i think of the male-female friendships that i have that lasted, i view those men are court eunuchs. i know that sounds bad, and this does not like reflect their actual sexual value, im not trying to invalidate their masculinity, but it’s true. i mentally castrated them, they are unfuckable. or sometimes some of them are just so ugly that they come castrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and if i have a male friend that i dont mentally castrate, they end up either being a) kept at an arms length, or b) friendship ends at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;like, i cant be friends with you mentally knowing that you have a third leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;im pretty sure it works differently for guys. i dont think guys mentally neuter women that often.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="opinion" /><summary type="html">guys i think i cooked with this one. lately i have this new theory.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Roxanne</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/fiction/2025/01/10/roxanne.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Roxanne" /><published>2025-01-10T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-10T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/fiction/2025/01/10/roxanne</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/fiction/2025/01/10/roxanne.html">&lt;p&gt;Roxanne,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to a Cha Chan Teng in Chinatown the other day. It reminded me of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two straws in a Hong Dau Bing. Add 5 dollars for an ice cream. Now there’s only one straw, and the cheap red beans they have in America simply do not compare. But I sat there and sobbed because I know I could never share a Hong Dau Bing with you ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a tango. I swore, in front of all my friends and yours, that I don’t want anything to do with you. And it was true. Your beauty disgusted me. It fascinated me. I am not used to pretty girls being nice to me like that. You taught me my first swear words. You offered me my first blunt. You turned me from a boy to a man. I lost myself within you, I loathe myself without you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a point in time when you trusted me. You gave me your past. Like the stepfather that left you, and the mother that abused you. I wanted to shield you from the pain. I thought I could save you. When I held you in my arms, I saw the sparkle of life and ambition underneath the makeup. I saw myself in you, young, lost, but hopeful. But I see it clearly now, you were born broken. There was opium inside of your system when you were born. There was no escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You traded your integrity for drugs, just like that pathetic mother of yours. You claim that you were pimped out by her, but I think we both know that it was you. And perhaps there is a part of your conscience that knows that this isn’t right, so much that you almost hung yourself with that yellow scarf on Lion Rock, but you were too scared. That was the most selfish thing you could have done to me. Nothing is sacred to you. You sold your body and soul just to get a hit. I tried helping you. I put myself on the line for you. I almost got arrested fighting for you. But it didn’t matter, you had already given up on yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your sickness was macabre, and I knew that was the end. But it wasn’t those symptoms that disgusted me, it was you. I left you because I loved you, and I don’t want to see you like this. They asked me if I am going to visit you. But seeing a walking corpse of you pains me. It angers me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You were and remain as the only muse of my craft. I was so proud of having you, but now I am just embarrassed to even think you could be saved. I still think of you daily, I still speak of you highly. I am preserving the very honor that you disposed. Your name is brought up every time I introduce myself, because there is residue of you inside me. But your friends have all trashed and deserted you. They won’t even mention you by name. But it will all be over, your imminent death is only a matter of time. The doctors said you will die a slow, painful death of withdrawal.  I will have the decency to attend your funeral, knowing that you don’t have the respect to stay alive for me. I will write your obituary very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a double decker bus in Vegas a couple months ago. I cried because it resembles you. Like your stepfather. Towering, confident, whitewashed. And then it dawned on me, I will spend the rest of my life chasing vestiges of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I can call you names like Roxanne like that song, or Heung Gong, or Hong Kong, but that would not change the fact that you have changed. Fuck you for forcing me to leave you. Fuck you for betraying someone who had been with you for 18 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;x&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">Roxanne,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ronis</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/personal/2024/12/02/ronis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ronis" /><published>2024-12-02T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-02T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/personal/2024/12/02/ronis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/personal/2024/12/02/ronis.html">&lt;p&gt;teenage roni had a lot of anger within her. ever since she gained class consciousness at 13 and got twitter, she had been really angry about all sorts of things. men, capitalism, bigotry, the socioeconomic state of the world. she didn’t understand how life could be so unfair. she turned her anger into words. she writes down pages and pages of angry notes, even if it’s grammatically incorrect. she has nowhere to express it other than instagram, so she created her own platform. you can blame it on the pick-meness, but, some part of her was delusional enough to believe that she could be the change she wanted to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then, teenage roni got older, and reality starts to hit. she finds out that it is unrealistic to major in english/ creative writing if she wants to make a shit ton of money. and she wants to make a shit ton of money because she discovers that socialism is impractical and unrealistic. she finds out that saying “i hate m*n” or “m*n are trash” on instagram stories does not stop that creep at the train station from harassing her, or catcalled on the streets even though she is wearing a hoodie and sweatpants. it also doesn’t stop her friend from asking “what were you wearing lol” when she confided about it. the anger slowly morphed from a desire to destroy to a learned willingness to succumb. she breathes in the smoke. if u can’t beat them, u join them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;teenage roni turned twenty. twenty-year-old roni reaped what teenage roni sowed: a life of hard work, great friends, strong opinions and earnest willpower to achieve. she is not going to back down. twenty-year-old roni was also fairly sure that men are trash, but she had been experimenting, because her friends and that little worm in her head told her it is embarrassing to be A0 at 20 lol. as such, twenty-year-old roni did a lot of things teenage roni would not ever expect she would do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at this point, most of the things teenage roni cared about: school, career, family, friends, all are fairly successful. she has teenage and twenty-year-old roni to thank for. but also because of something twenty-year-old roni did, she now has some extra bullshit she has to put up with. and those were not taught at school, she had to rely on youtubers to instruct her. teenage roni would know exactly what to do, but twenty-one-year-old roni feels too embarrassed to wake her up and ask for help. teenage roni would be disappointed in her, so it’s best if we could just let her rest. twenty-one-year-old roni just wishes teenage roni would forgive her if she ever finds out. knowing her, teenage roni would probably call her a dumb bitch. she’s probably not wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but to twenty-one-year-old roni’s credit, she discovered more within her. she is much more kinder and sweeter than what she’s led herself to believe. her self perception is quite warped; by that I mean, teenage roni thinks she some heartless evil maneater femme fatale that is immune to emotional vulnerability and incapable of love… but that could not be further from the truth. modern society wants to shame sentimentalists like her for overthinking, but, it is actually deeply rewarding to wield a mind as introspective and imaginative as hers. to weave stories with words, to mend wounds with ingenuity. teenage roni locks that love behind a firewall of jest and logical deduction, but if you ever get a chance to encounter it, she will love fiercely. and twenty-one-year-old roni was so, so close to killing that love within her for all the trouble it has caused, but, love is not the problem. it never was. don’t let the age of nonchalance and idgaf wars fool you. only cowards kill the parts of themselves that care. you just got to guard that love carefully, because it is so, so precious and delicate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;twenty-one-year-old roni is now trying to figure out what to do from here on out. not to be pessimistic, but, the possibilities are decreasing at an exponential rate. still, there is no need to fret. like the instagram reel dating coach ladies said, what’s yours will find you. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">teenage roni had a lot of anger within her. ever since she gained class consciousness at 13 and got twitter, she had been really angry about all sorts of things. men, capitalism, bigotry, the socioeconomic state of the world. she didn’t understand how life could be so unfair. she turned her anger into words. she writes down pages and pages of angry notes, even if it’s grammatically incorrect. she has nowhere to express it other than instagram, so she created her own platform. you can blame it on the pick-meness, but, some part of her was delusional enough to believe that she could be the change she wanted to see.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dear 21 Year Old Me</title><link href="https://inherownwrite.com/birthday/2024/11/04/dear-21-year-old-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear 21 Year Old Me" /><published>2024-11-04T23:14:45-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T23:14:45-08:00</updated><id>https://inherownwrite.com/birthday/2024/11/04/dear-21-year-old-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://inherownwrite.com/birthday/2024/11/04/dear-21-year-old-me.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear 21 Year Old Me,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the first draft of this on the flight to Vegas, but I forgot to finish it and it was on a diff. laptop. So I will start over. And it took me a month and a half to write this, so technically I am the 21-year-old talking to my 21-year-old self. I apologize, but it has indeed been quite a crazy year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do I even start? I guess we should pick up from where we left off, November 2023. You were knees deep in the first semester in Berkeley, gaslighting yourself into thinking everything is okay. being 20 actually turned a whole new page for me, life-wise, career-wise, and on a personal level. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can feel myself getting more practical and practical. Bending for capitalism. Bending to reality. Well, it is about damn time anyways, after all, you signed your full-time offer. You used to be so angry at the whole world. Angry about wars, capitalism, politics, etc… but at some point, you learn to live with it. And you begin to feel helpless instead of being angry. Because most things are beyond your control. You turned your anger into frustration, and frustration turns into helplessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told myself to follow through my goals last year. I think I somewhat got out of my comfort zone and worked harder on my discipline and goals: for example, I actually consistently went to the gym. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a simple goal for you this year: live in the moment. How dare you call yourself an ENFP when all you do is worry about your next move? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while I’m at it, you also haven’t written much this year, after your creative writing course. Please, contain your media consumption and do things that fulfill you instead of draining you. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>In Her Own Write</name></author><category term="birthday" /><summary type="html">Dear 21 Year Old Me,</summary></entry></feed>