<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-08T13:37:33+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">In Her Own Write</title><subtitle>This is the place where I talk about stuff that's too meta for Insta.</subtitle><author><name>Veronica Cheung</name></author><entry><title type="html">In Her Own Write</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/08/in-her-own-write.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In Her Own Write" /><published>2020-04-08T13:10:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-08T13:10:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/08/in-her-own-write</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/08/in-her-own-write.html">&lt;p&gt;The topic I am going to discuss today is quite monumental: the story behind &lt;i&gt;In Her Own Write&lt;/i&gt;. It is only the matter of time before I run out of topics to write about, so just hang on tight and I will try my best to the meaning behind &lt;i&gt;“In Her Own Write”&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us start from the beginning. I was trying to explain something on my Instagram stories, something regarding my summer job. But at one point,  I have come to realise that my power is beyond Instagram story posts. The thoughts in my head are yearning for emancipation. I need an audience, so a diary would never work, but at the same time, I do not care about the number of people who looks at my stuff. I just want to know that my brain can ripple someone somewhere to reflect. The fact that you, yes you right here, is reading this, is the testimony that my thoughts are valued. With the never-ending quarantine, I believe that the only way to release my big brain energy, the only way to put the eternal malaise of my soul at ease, is to start a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t tell, I was getting ahead of myself. I always get in-too-deep with my own writing, so let’s get back to the point. It took me 3 minutes to plan but 3 days to handle the technical parts of building this site. (I used Jekyll, for those who are interested.) All of the pictures in the pages (not the posts) are taken by yours truly during my trip to America this summer, and I think they fit the aesthetic quite well. The working title of this blog was (VeronicaBlog), but I knew I needed something more charismatic, something more boujee to give it a dash of pizzazz. I want to give this site life of its own because it should not be attached to my name; it is its own being, and I am no more than its creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Lennon published 2 books in his 40 years on earth, &lt;i&gt;In His Own Write&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;A Spaniard in the Works&lt;/i&gt;. (His third and final one &lt;i&gt;Skywriting by Word of Mouth&lt;/i&gt; was published posthumously in 1986, it does not count.) While Lennon’s cultural impact in literature goes much further than these two non-sensical, hardly-good books, I adore his sense of humour in them. Most prominently, I really like the puns in the titles. You see, &lt;i&gt;In His Own Write&lt;/i&gt; is a wordplay on the phrase “in his own right”, meaning he has earned it by himself and not because of anyone else. I must admit that I was immediately drawn to the book by its title, yet the content itself is as non-sensical as you can &lt;i&gt;imagine&lt;/i&gt;. There is hardly any punctuation throughout the book. But that is not what we are here for, yes I did blatantly stole the title of his book and changed the pronoun of it. Call me a fraud and I could not care any less, Lennon probably stole the pun from somewhere else. So yes, the origin of &lt;i&gt;In Her Own Write&lt;/i&gt; is just to pay homage (to steal a pun) from John Winston Ono Lennon, one of my personal heroes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think about it, this actually makes so much sense. “In one’s own right“ means that something is because of your own ability, effort, or situation and not because of anyone or anything else, and indeed this site is a reflection of my own situation, my own ability and my own thoughts. And to pun it into “In Her Own Write” infuses the idea that my writing is the outcome of me in-too-deep of my own thoughts. I am figuratively and literally giving you a piece of my mind. Quite genius if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I confess that this entire idea is pretentious and self-important. &lt;i&gt;Thoughts ain’t worth a dime.&lt;/i&gt; But yeah, being pretentious, edgy and egotistic is one of my online personality traits, and I am showing that side here unapologetically. (I must admit that I have lied in the previous statement, I am very insecure about the outcome of this entire project and please don’t hate me I am just trying to work on something in my spare time ahahahah XD)  I mean, &lt;i&gt;fake it till you make it&lt;/i&gt;, right? I find writing here highly therapeutic. It is like finally coming to terms with my inner untamed thoughts, and though I am not an extrovertedly creative person, &lt;i&gt;“je pense, donc je suis”&lt;/i&gt;. Don’t mind me throwing tastelessly pompous words around, that is my idea of good writing. And I swear I am not like this in real life, I don’t see myself as a narcissist at all, it is just my mind that amazes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the domain inherownwrite.com was already taken by the time I came up with this name. Never mind that, I would not know how to set up other domains so &lt;a href=&quot;https://inherownwrite.github.io&quot;&gt;inherownwrite.github.io&lt;/a&gt; might be the best possible name I can give for this site. I presume that this is the first article you have read from me, and that is splendid because it only goes downhill from here. Expect daily posts here every day except Thursdays and Sundays (unless otherwise notified), with pretentious topics like film review, music review, book review and thoughts review, with even more pretentious wordings. Mind that grammar mistakes may be present, but that would be Grammarly’s fault, not mine. I thank you kindly for reading all this and I hope to see you here tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;P.S. The cover picture here is the NYC sky just outside of the Dakota, where Lennon was assassinated. Copyright to me. Quite proud of this one.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;p&gt;#InHerOwnWrite&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Veronica Cheung</name></author><summary type="html">The topic I am going to discuss today is quite monumental: the story behind In Her Own Write. It is only the matter of time before I run out of topics to write about, so just hang on tight and I will try my best to the meaning behind “In Her Own Write”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Thrill of It All</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/07/the-thrill-of-it-all.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Thrill of It All" /><published>2020-04-07T21:30:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T21:30:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/07/the-thrill-of-it-all</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/07/the-thrill-of-it-all.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Looking Back&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no concrete definition of a “thrill” whatsoever. It might be a sense of excitement you get when you find things intriguing and awesome. The thrill is subjective because not everyone understands what it takes to make themselves stimulated. In fact, looking at the situation of our world right now, I am hardly excited. I just want to reminisce and learn what it takes to feel the excitement in life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a ‘thrill’? The immediate answer I have in mind is euphoria. Of course, we feel magnificent when we anticipate, this is precisely why people make count-downs. We long for the future, we long for that specific event, object or person to come and sweep us off our feet. And that feeling is great because, in that period of time, you have a purpose in life. And when you have a purpose in life, you have a reason to live, right? Sounds divine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I have dramatised this a little too much. But it happens to me every time something remotely “cool” occurs in life: a package I just ordered from Kylie Cosmetics, a concert to attend to next month, my graduation in year… The thought of this makes me excited. I would idealise this as something riveting and absolutely life-changing, overhyping that to the point of no return. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad thing about excitement though, is that it never lasts. The span from euphoria to disappointment is so short that it comes and goes within the snap of a finger, barely noticeable. It is the tension, the build-up leading to the coming of the package that makes the thrill of it all. The worst part about this is that YOU determine the value of the thrill. If you track that package every 5 mins and think about it every 2 seconds, you give value to the thrill. Once the waiting game is over, you are back to boredom and misery. The thrill never lives up to the standard either. Absolutely nothing changes. Life goes on, and you don’t feel any better.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some way, the thrill is a drug. You get high and all is well, you depend on that happiness for so long, and when it escapes from you you feel nothing but hollowness and dullness. And we depend on it, too, because it gives us purpose. The “thrill” completes us, whether it is the thrill of tomorrow, the thrill of superficial materialism, or the thrill of goals and dreams. In the following song, &lt;I&gt;The Thrill is Gone&lt;/I&gt; by B. B. King, the lyrics perfectly describe the chill numbness one experiences after the lover leaves them “for good”.  &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;iframe width=&quot;315&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kpC69qIe02E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(2:20)&lt;br&gt;&lt;I&gt;Oh, the thrill is gone, baby&lt;br&gt;It’s gone away for good&lt;br&gt;Someday, I know I’ll be over it all, baby&lt;br&gt;Just like I know a man should&lt;br&gt;You know I’m free, free now, baby&lt;br&gt;I’m free from your spell&lt;/I&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Even though we do not know if the narrator of this song is just comforting himself to say that she had left for good or not, we  can still feel the sadness in his voice, how he misses the ecstatic thrill of intoxication this lover of his provides. (For a cool, revamped, 10-minute version of this song with Eric Clapton click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SgXSomPE_FY&quot;&gt;here)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Right Now&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What goes up must come down. And it is saddening because it takes time to find something else to look forward to. Looking at our society and my generation right now, our lives may feel a bit &lt;I&gt;lacklustre&lt;/I&gt;. There is absolutely no thrill in life! Concerts are cancelled, school is cancelled, hell the person you stan might also be cancelled. Personally, I need something to look forward to for me to keep my faith in humanity. But when all homework is done and all dues are paid, the thrill is also used up. I would not want to admit that in front of anyone, because the optimistic nihilist in me always thinks YOLO whatevs. Yet, when there is not much to look to, it is hard not to feel numb. I guess we are used to the thrill. I am addicted to the thrill. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the final, “inspirational&quot; point I want to bring out is to find thrill in small things. As we grow older and stuff gets more serious, the thrill will leave us. We will stop getting excited for dumb things like package and concerts, and before you even notice this quarantine will end and you will realise how much time you have wasted waiting for the “thrill” to come. Ending this on a happy note, here is a song from the film &lt;I&gt;Tangled&lt;/I&gt; (one of my favourite Disney films) named  &lt;I&gt; “When Will My Life Begin”&lt;/I&gt;. Rapunzel has been stuck in quarantine like us for 18 years, but she still finds joy in her life. While she wonders when will her adventure begin, she keeps a productive daily routine for herself and worked very hard to do chores and candle-making and stuff. One of the reasons I started this site is also to keep myself busy with small but fun interests. We can all learn from Rapunzel and mature in life by practising self-care and routinely pastimes that you might not have time doing before.  When the day finally comes, you may look back and tell yourself that you have utilised the months you had quarantining. The thrill of it all is quite meaningless, so by diminishing its value and staying satisfied with small things, it will eventually get better. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K_AyUovLL7Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Veronica Cheung</name></author><summary type="html">Looking Back There is no concrete definition of a “thrill” whatsoever. It might be a sense of excitement you get when you find things intriguing and awesome. The thrill is subjective because not everyone understands what it takes to make themselves stimulated. In fact, looking at the situation of our world right now, I am hardly excited. I just want to reminisce and learn what it takes to feel the excitement in life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ratatouille, Revisited</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/06/ratatouille-revisited.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ratatouille, Revisited" /><published>2020-04-06T12:45:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-06T12:45:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/06/ratatouille-revisited</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/06/ratatouille-revisited.html">&lt;p&gt; In dark times like this, we all might need some escape to forget about all the bad stuff happening in reality. That is why last night, after a long day of dabbling into the world of Jekyll, Ruby, Rubygems and other kinds of coding stuff (I won’t go into it but it is highly stressful), I’ve decided to just sit back and watch &lt;I&gt; Ratatouille (2008) &lt;/I&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/02JIdsrod3BYucThfUFDUX&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Crazy how it’s been 12 years since the film came out. Like 2008 does not seem that long ago, with Beijing Olympics and stuff. I think I’ve watched this film on Disney Channel before(like 8/9pm wish when they start playing random movies), but I already forgot 90% of it. A film critic YouTuber I watch &lt;a url = “https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCS85PXHRkizrbGHBCe4tV3g”&gt;Karsten Runquist&lt;/a&gt; actually reminded me to rewatch this Pixar classic. He ranked &lt;I&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/I&gt; as his favourite Pixar film, over Toy Story and Wall-E, so there might be something special about it that might take a second viewing to discover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would describe &lt;I&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/I&gt; as a very warm and heartfelt film. It does not pack itself as a cinematic masterpiece, nor does it display itself as a slapstick, mindless children’s movie. It is something in between. Most of this film takes part in the kitchen, and boy does the kitchen serves the warm, beautiful colour tones very well. The cityscape of Paris is equally breathtaking, I can’t imagine how disappointed children could be when the actual Paris does not actually look like the city of lights. (Not trying to be mean to Paris but, yeah it is more like a dumpster now.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot is not actually the strongest part about the film I think, it is the characters that are so memorable. Remy represents the ambitious, the mighty part of us that is physically incapable to fulfil our goals. You can call him the underdog (rat) with a dream. As for Linguini, while I find his character quite bland, he represents the insecurities and things that are holding us back, not actually realising his full potential at hand. Together, they are capable of doing the impossible and fulfilling their dreams together, hand in hand (hair). It is the little rat that matters, and even though this story is no less than a modern fairytale, it hits home at its imaginative, inspiring core: &lt;I&gt; anyone can cook&lt;/I&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I could critique about this film is how they treated the *only female* character, Colette. To me, she is the feisty, spirited woman who would come off as mean and bitter, but only to defend herself against the patriarchal world. Even if she fits into a certain female character trope, I still like her very much. BUT SHE DOESN’T NEED A LOVE STORY! She doesn’t need Linguini the garbage boy to be the baddest. I find their love story quite forced and unnatural. Sure, I can’t think of a better explanation for Linguini’s storyline, but STILL!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to keep these at the minimal word count and not to bore you, but yeah this ended on quite a negative note. &lt;I&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/I&gt; is still a great film to just sit back and enjoy, I recommend rewatching it really even just for the nostalgia. We all wish for simpler times and simpler realities, where the worst thing that could happen is a talking rat cooking in your kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Veronica Cheung</name></author><summary type="html">In dark times like this, we all might need some escape to forget about all the bad stuff happening in reality. That is why last night, after a long day of dabbling into the world of Jekyll, Ruby, Rubygems and other kinds of coding stuff (I won’t go into it but it is highly stressful), I’ve decided to just sit back and watch Ratatouille (2008) .</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why People Hate Baby Nut</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/05/why-people-hate-baby-nut-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why People Hate Baby Nut" /><published>2020-04-05T16:16:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-05T16:16:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/05/why-people-hate-baby-nut-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/05/why-people-hate-baby-nut-1.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;(This article is discontinued/to be continued. Originally written on Febuary 6 2020 for my self-titled essay collection, the next part of this article will be published in the forseeable future.)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contains spoilers for: The RIP Mr Peanut commercial, the Baby Nut Super Bowl Commercial, the Guardians of the Galaxy and the Mandalorian&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet People love the Baby trend: first we had Baby Groot, then Baby Yoda and even Baby Sonic. Baby Nut is the newest mascot for company Planters, continuing Mr. Peanut’s legacy when he died saving two random actors in a ‘car crash’ a week ago. The original idea of Baby Nut is that he had risen from Mr Peanut’s grave and Kool-Aid’s tears, which gave him the miracle of life and in turn became the newest internet sensation/meme. After the initial release of the Super Bowl commercial of his birth, fans of Planters and the internet mob raged on the internet and collectively hate Baby Nut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is safe to say that people don’t response well to the birth of Baby Nut. Twitter user @21sDagger expressed his rage under Baby Nut’s post, ‘I’m going to kill baby peanut man’, followed by a picture of a sledgehammer and a crushed peanut. @stonecolddadi69 attacked Baby Nut tweeting, ‘I want to squish stupid lil baby nut with my bare hands I hate him’ along with a GIF of Baby Nut dancing. When @TOZIERCLOUD asked @uhohbabey what did Baby nut ever do to her, @uhohbabey replied, ‘look at those stupid little baby hands. And his stupid little eyes. i hope he suffers the pain of a thousand fiery deaths’. Baby Nut has become the newest internet meme, with people hating on Baby Nut to the point where they would make peanut butter from Baby Nut’s organs and give it to Baby Yoda. But why do people hate Baby Nut so much? What does this say about our society?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To explore this topic further, we must first learn why companies uses mascots. Planters’ original mascot, the late Mr. Peanut, has been one of the most iconic mascots in the 20th Century, with his face printed on every single can of peanuts they produce. Mascots are typically used to capture the target audience’s attention, build an emotion connection and establish a recognisable personality for the brand. Mr. Peanut has been around since 1916, was previously voiced by actors Robert Downey Jr. and Bill Hader and is widely known as  one of the most famous mascots alongside M&amp;Ms and Tony the Tiger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peanut has been around for 104 years. Perhaps that is exactly why the marketing department of Planters decided to switch it up and follow the baby trend of babifying characters: Disney has got it. Baby Groot and Baby Yoda has appealed to the mass and became successful internet sensations, with fans sending nothing but love and protection to these cute babies. Baby Groot was born after his predecessor (regular) Groot sacrificed himself for his friends in film Guardians of the Galaxy, having a tragic yet heartwarming backstory. The origin of Baby Yoda (official known as ‘The Child’) is still unknown, but one theory suggests that he is the biological offspring of Star Wars characters Yoda and Yaddle, that Yaddle was killed by terrorists after a attack on her planet, leaving Baby Yoda orphaned (that is before the title character of The Mandalorian adopted him). With the success of these Disney babies, advertising agency for Planters probably thought that it would be a good idea to ‘revamp’ the Planters brand a bit. Here is how it probably went in the marketing pitching meeting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘We should kill off Mr. Peanut by making him sacrifice for his friends, then make Kool-Aid shed a tear on his very grave to respawn a baby version of Mr. Peanut. Just like Baby Groot.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Excellent idea, Connor. What should we call the new baby?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Baby... Peanut?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘No Darryl, Baby Peanut is too predictable. How about Baby Nut?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Wouldn’t that be a bit inappropriate?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘What is?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Never mind.’&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;   I believe that two major factors resulting in the collective Baby Nut hate are: the unnecessary, commercialised backstory of his birth, and the unoriginal instinct to follow internet culture. First, let us go through the problem with his backstory. One may argue that his backstory is worked for Baby Groot and Baby Yoda, so theoretically it should work for Baby Nut too. However, the advertising agency overestimated the emotional value a peanut’s death could have for its audience. To put it simple, nobody cares about Mr. Peanut’s death. Indeed they copied Groot’s backstory by having him to sacrifice for his friends, hence making him a hero, but it does not add depth to his characters. Nobody would shed a tear for the advertisement. Groot’s death has an emotional value because the audience has familiarised themselves to these characters for 2 hours before it happened, and everyone felt the power of friendship and family when he gave his life to protect his friends. On the other hand, we had no clue what Mr. Peanut was like before this commercial. All we knew was that he is probably very rich (hence the top hat and monocle), he has this stupid peanut car named the nutmobile and that he is the dumb guy from Planters. His death lacked depth to the story. All we see from the ad was an unnecessary marketing move by Planters, and that they are trying so hard to make #RIPeanut trend on Twitter. (Planters, stop trying to make #RIPeanut happen, it’s not going to happen.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People were already done with Mr. Peanut after the first commercial surfaced. Everyone was talking about how dumb this was, but then came Baby Nut. The commercial itself was not at all bad, you can see its high production value of the CGI and actors. However, it is the storyline of the advertisement that falls short. Mr Peanut has been resurrected by Kool-Aid’s tear and has risen as Baby Nut from his grave. This has made Mr Peanut’s sacrifice seemed like a farce, something that has been used just for shock value. There was nothing touching or emotionally impactful about Baby Nut’s birth; all we see is a stupid commercial. They could have just made Mr Peanut get married to another Peanut and have Baby Nut together, and nobody would be pissed about it. Through this advertisement that nobody asked for, Planters has shown their out of touch with the audience of their advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt; To be continued... &lt;/i&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Veronica Cheung</name></author><summary type="html">(This article is discontinued/to be continued. Originally written on Febuary 6 2020 for my self-titled essay collection, the next part of this article will be published in the forseeable future.) Contains spoilers for: The RIP Mr Peanut commercial, the Baby Nut Super Bowl Commercial, the Guardians of the Galaxy and the Mandalorian</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">bundle exec jekyll serve</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/04/bundle-exec-jekyll-serve.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="bundle exec jekyll serve" /><published>2020-04-04T13:10:09+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T13:10:09+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/04/bundle-exec-jekyll-serve</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/04/bundle-exec-jekyll-serve.html">&lt;p&gt;I can't figure out stupid Github pages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I'm the stupid one. I've been trying to figure out this for so long, I don't even know if this is &quot;worth it&quot; haha. I haven't even finished my IES. I guess I'll just stay here and I dunno, work all day again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I asked on StackOverflow, and I hope some middle-aged white dude will answer my question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, things to work as well as you want them to be, but you just gotta accept it and hustle. That is something I've learned after 3-4 years of dabbling in coding, I guess. When I can't seem to figure out this ONE particular problem in my site, the final solution (well not final but, a desperate choice nonetheless) I have is to ask the Internet. And the Internet is full of white tech dudebros. In fact, a French possibly dudebro gave me a potential solution to my StackOverflow question but, I think I am way too proud to try his solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is also something I've been trying to work on. Sometimes I find myself too humble/ awkward with people. We used to idolize the higher form students at our school, but now when we are the juniors and seniors, we don't feel a particular sense of superiority. That might be due to the fact that kids nowadays are meaner/ more disrespectful, but I would have loved to feel that kind of 'I am older therefore I'm wiser' kind of mood. Now, when I give suggestions to reporters as the sub-editor of our school magazine, I would put 'haha's, 'lol's and 'i guess' after my constructive criticisms, to lighten the mood and to make my comment less mean. That is totally not necessary but, I'm awkward in that kind of way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other times, I am egotistic. I am too proud and pretentious. I used to post videos that I am proud of to Instagram/ Facebook and now I look back it is just the highest purest form of cringe. We all do embarrassing things when we were young, but sometimes I get a sense of entitlement from myself. Like 'I think I am cooler than you, so I am posting this to prove that'. Same goes to the Spotify screenshots and Netflix-tilted-what-I-am-watching stories. I don't want to look like a show-off, I don't think I am trying to be one, but it comes off as a pretentious douchebag move. I don't want to be judged in this way. And this goes BACK to my 'too awkward' problem. On one hand, I should not care what other people think about my posts. 'I am not trying to be pretentious here. If you don't like my stuff, you can leave.' and 'I am sorry to bother you, is this stupid? I am trying too hard to be edgy.' The eternal dilemma haunts me every time I post something to my Instagram stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, if any dudebro answers my noob question on StackOverflow, I will politely thank him but at the same time despise him for being smarter than me. It's almost like I am a hybrid of Hufflepuff and Slytherin.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Veronica Cheung</name></author><summary type="html">I can't figure out stupid Github pages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Things First</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/03/first-things-first.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Things First" /><published>2020-04-03T12:58:09+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-03T12:58:09+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/03/first-things-first</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/03/first-things-first.html">&lt;p&gt;I hope I can somehow “inspire” you to do stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, one of my goals this break is to not let one part of myself define my entire being. What I mean by that is I don’t want to display just one interest/ hobby/ personality of mine define lolurnotveronica. I like music, I like films, I like my turtles, but I’m much more than that. I think one of the main problems with social media (there are a LOT of problems) is that people tend to define themselves to one certain aspect. like your appearance, your sports team, your school stuff, your food and your travels. I don’t know how to fix that, cuz deep down all we want is to display the best part of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is no “best part of ourselves”. There are a hundred layers to a person. And it is hard to display all of that in one, instagram story. The worst part is, we don’t want others to know the ugly parts of ourselves. so when people post stuff about themselves, they only post the cool stuff to make ppl like them. That is completely fine, like we would do that already social media or not. The problem is, it creates an illusory persona that might make us feel like we need to live ‘up’ to that standard. For example, photoshopping yourself makes you look cooler. But if you photoshop every single picture of yourself, it makes you think that people would only like you if you look like your photoshop self. Truth is, you will never be satisfied. The person in that picture is no longer ‘you’. That, my friend, is the ‘you’ you want people to look at, to believe that is you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I bringing this up? Because I want to start this blog/ online journal thing to start sharing other part of lolurnotveronica. A part that, still, would be semi-idealistic and too-cool-for-instagram, but at least I can share something. I wanna talk about things that are not always displayed through Instagram stories, parts of me that I want to share but might come off as ‘pretentious’ and annoying just to spam everyone. This is like a glimpse of my brain and opinions that I’ve always wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not ‘the best part of myself’. But it certainly is one part of lolurnotveronica. I don’t have perfect grammar or perfect writing styles, but I think you don’t need that to share things effectively. Actually you do but, whatever I have Grammarly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might also do some movie reviews, fav book of the week, spotify playlist etc. All kinds of pretentious stuff that I feel uncomfortable doing on Instagram stories. You can't judge the content here, right? This is literally my show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Veronica Cheung</name></author><summary type="html">I hope I can somehow “inspire” you to do stuff.</summary></entry></feed>